She was trying to find you where.
她想找到你在哪里。
So real quick,
所以，很快，
actually, the facilities people actually just came to me
事实上，设施的人刚刚来找我，
and they said that the governor is here, Shapiro,
他们说州长在这里， Shapiro ，
I support him, he's not a Trump supporter,
我支持他，他不是 Trump 的支持者，
but the main entrance is blocked off,
但主入口被封锁了，
so when the class is over,
所以当课程结束时，
you can't go through that entrance,
你不能通过那个入口，
you got to take the elevator and go upstairs,
你得乘电梯上楼，
that's why all the fedies and the cops are out there.
所以联邦探员和警察都在外面。
All right, so again for the class,
好的，对于课程，
again, we had the recitation on Monday,
我们在星期一有一次复习课，
that's been posted on piazza as a video,
作为一个视频发布在了 Piazza 上，
project #1 is still due on October 7th, October 2nd,
项目一截止 10 月 2 日，
and then we will have again the special office hours on Saturday on October 1st,
然后，我们将在 10 月 1 日星期六有特殊办公时间，
and then homework #1 has been bumped to be due on October 4th,
然后作业二推迟到 10 月 4 日，
and that's a Wednesday, not a Sunday.
那是星期三，而不是星期天。
Any questions about the homework and the projects?
关于作业和项目有什么问题吗？
All right, so it's, it's due on the, it's due on the Sunday
好的，它是星期天截止，
and then the office hours are on the Saturday,
然后办公时间在星期六，
so whatever those real dates are?
所以不论真正的日期是什么？
Yes.
是的。
The website and GradeScope should be correct, I'm not.
网站和 GradeScope 应该是正确的，不是我。
Other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
All right, cool.
好的，酷。
So then two sort of, one sort of fun thing to bring up,
所以，有一个有趣的事情，
someone said hey, what about internships, are these companies hiring,
有人说，嘿，实习怎么样，这些公司在招人吗，
the answer is yes,
答案是肯定的，
and actually somebody posted out on Twitter,
事实上，有人在推特上发帖说，
that you know if you take my class they're hiring,
你知道如果你上我的课，他们就会招人，
spacetime_db is a I I think it's time, another time series database system,
spacetime_db ，我想它是另一个时间序列数据库系统，
I think it's at Europe,
我想是在欧洲，
I don't know this dude,
我不认识这家伙，
you can contact him if you want,
如果你愿意，你可以联系他，
but we'll post on Piazza,
但我们会在 Piazza 上张贴，
how you know how, how you can give me your your CV
如何给我你的简历，
and then we can send it to the various database companies that we know
然后我们可以把它发送给我们认识的各种数据库公司，
and that are friends with us,
以及与我们是朋友的公司，
and again if you haven't yet, please apply to SingleStore
如果你还没有，请向 SingleStore 申请，
and there's that special email address that's just for CMU students
那里有一个专门针对 CMU 学生的特殊电子邮件地址，
and that'll go directly to the hiring people and not the recruiters.
它会直接发给招聘者，而不是招聘人员。
So if you don't want to do an internship,
如果你不想做实习，
another way to make money through databases is that,
另一种通过数据库赚钱的方法是，
somebody actually posted an upwork and this is real,
有人在 upwork 上发布，这是真实的，
that they're looking for someone to basically design database projects,
他们正在寻找人来设计数据库项目，
that are basically ButTub and the class projects,
基本上就是 BusTub 和课程项目，
so if you like the stuff you're doing,
所以，如果你喜欢你正在做的事情，
you can get paid a hundred dollars by this guy
你可以从这个人那里得到 100 美元的报酬，
to go re-implement that.
让你去重新实现它。
And the way we found this was
我们发现这件事的方式是，
somebody actually emailed Chi the TA and me,
有人给我和 TA Chi 发了电子邮件，
like, hey, I can do this job for you
说，嘿，我可以为你做这份工作，
and he's like what are you talking about,
他就像是，你在说什么，
because they thought we posted this,
因为他们以为我们发了这个，
this is not us, this is [],
这不是我们，这是[]，
hundred dollars not enough,
一百美元肯定不够，
hundred dollars an hour, in databases,
每小时一百美元在数据库上，
if not more.
如果不是更多的话。
All right, so where we at in the class,
好的，我们课程的哪里，
we, we spent the last week or so talking again about the storage layer
我们花了大约一周的时间讨论了存储层，
and then putting the buffer pool on top of it
然后将缓冲池放在它的上面，
to actually manage memory as we get pages in and out of of disk,
以便在我们将页面传入和传出磁盘时管理内存，
and so now we're continuing up the stack
所以，现在我们继续向上，
and are now going to talk about different parts of the system,
现在将讨论系统的不同部分，
that can operate and execute and process those pages,
这些部分可以操作、执行和处理这些页面，
that we've brought into our buffer pool that we retrieved from disk.
我们从磁盘检索到的缓冲池中的（页面）。
And so we're sort of in this middle layer here, in the Access Methods,
所以，我们处于中间层，在访问方法，
and now we're going start talking about
现在我们将开始讨论，
how do we construct the execution engine,
如何构建执行引擎，
that's going to be responsible for executing these queries.
负责执行这些查询。
And so the access method is going to be the mechanisms for accessing the data,
访问方法是访问数据的机制，
and it could either be through an index or through the tables themselves
它可以通过索引或通过表本身，
and potentially other mechanisms.
也可以通过其他机制。
So to do that, we need to talk about
要做到这个，我们需要讨论，
what kind of data structures we would have, this part of the system,
我们将在系统的这一部分拥有什么样的数据结构，
and so this class will be on hash tables,
所以这节课将是哈希表，
which is an unordered data structure,
这是一种无序数据结构，
and then we'll spend all of next week talking about tree data structures,
然后我们将在整个下周讨论树形数据结构，
which will give you ordering, give you ordering your own keys.
它会给你排序，给你自己的键排序。
And so we're just slowly building up,
所以，我们是在慢慢地积累，
making our way to the top
通过我们的方式达到顶端，
to actually produce results for our queries.
为我们的查询产生结果。
So, I mean, it goes with sort out saying,
所以，我的意思是，
I'm assuming everyone here is taken a data structure class or algorithms class,
我假设这里的每个人都学习了数据结构课程或算法课程，
data structures are going to be used all throughout the system,
数据结构将在整个系统中使用，
and we've already covered in some ways and some, some parts of the system so far
到目前为止，我们已经在某些方面涵盖了系统的一些部分，
are where we're going to use these, these things.
我们将在哪里使用这些东西。
But there be other parts of it,
但还有其他方面的原因，
we need to have high performance, safe and correct data structures
我们需要有高性能，安全和正确的数据结构，
to represent state of the system or the data of the system.
来表示系统状态或系统数据。
So we've already seen how we can use this for internal metadata,
我们已经了解了如何将其用于内部元数据，
we talked about the page directory or the page table,
我们谈到了页目录或页表，
that's more or less a hash table
这或多或少是一个哈希表，
being used to map page IDs to some location on disk or some location in memory.
用于将页面 ID 映射到磁盘上的某个位置或内存中的某个位置。
We could use the data structures for the core storage of the tables themselves,
我们可以将数据结构用于表本身的核心存储，
remember, we talked about the the index-organized tables,
我们谈到了索引组织的表，
where the actual tuples themselves would be in the leaf nodes of the B+ tree,
其中 tuple 本身将位于 B+ 树的叶节点中，
so you could have your tables actually just be represented directly in in a data structure
所以，你可以将表直接表示在数据结构中，
rather than unordered [] files.
而不是无序的[]文件中。
We could also use these data structures for query execution
我们还可以将这些数据结构用于查询执行，
to generate ephemeral or temporary collections of data,
以生成临时数据集合，
that allows to execute queries more efficiently,
允许更高效地执行查询，
this is basically how we're going to implement hash join very fast
这就是我们将如何实现 hash join 很快，
or how implement joins very quickly using hash joins,
或者如何使用 hash join 实现 join 很快，
so we build a hash table on the fly,
我们动态构建一个哈希表，
populate with the data from the tables or scanning,
使用表或扫描中的数据进行填充，
do the join and then throw the hash table away,
执行 join ，然后丢弃哈希表，
so just because, you know we're building hash [],
所以，因为们构建哈希[]，
it doesn't mean it's going to stick around for a long, a long time,
不意味着它会长期存在，
and then probably the one you're most familiar with is
然后，你最熟悉的可能是，
using these data structures for table indexes,
将这些数据结构用于表索引，
when you call CREATE INDEX,
当调用 CREATE INDEX 时，
that's essentially going to create one of these data structures,
实质上将创建一个这样的数据结构，
and populate it with the keys
然后用键填充它，
and map them to the tuples,
并将它们映射到 tuple ，
so you do faster lookups,
这样你就可以更快地进行查找，
like a glossary in a textbook.
就像教科书中的词汇表一样。
So again, we'll see, we'll see these data structures being used
所以，我们将看到这些数据结构被使用，
throughout the rest of the semester
在本学期余下的时间里，
in different scenarios that are covered in this list here.
在这个列表中涵盖的不同场景中。
So now what do we care about when we design our data structures,
那么，当我们设计数据结构时，我们关心的是什么，
what are the things we need to be cognitive of,
我们需要认识到什么，
to make sure that we have an efficient database system,
以确保我们拥有一个有效的数据库系统，
that actually is also correct, which is very important, right.
而且也是正确的，这是非常重要的。
So the first thing you've got to worry about is,
所以你要担心的第一件事是，
how we're actually going to organize the, the, the data structure itself,
我们如何组织数据本身，
in either in memory
无论在内存中，
or pages that will be in memory but backed by by disk in the buffer pool.
或者在内存中但由缓冲池中的磁盘支持的页面。
And remember, I said in the beginning,
我在一开始就说过，
we want to make design choices in how we implement our system,
我们希望在如何实现我们的系统做出设计选择，
if we know it's going to be backed by pages on disk,
如果我们知道它将由磁盘上的页面支持，
that we maximize the amount of sequential I/O,
我们就会最大限度地增加顺序 I/O 的数量。
So maybe we'll lay out the pages in such a way,
所以，我们可能会以这样一种方式布局页面，
the data structure, in such a way,
这种方式的数据结构，
that we have long strides of data that we can read and write through multiple pages
这样我们就可以通过多个页面读取和写入数据，
instead of doing random I/O.
而不是进行随机 I/O 。
And then we'll talk about how do we actually make our data structures thread safe,
然后我们将讨论如何使我们的数据结构是线程安全的，
and so for this class, we won't really worry about it,
在这节课上，我们不用担心这个问题，
but we'll spend a whole lecture next week on Thursday or Wednesday next week,
但我们会在下周的周四或周三花一整节课的时间，
talk about how do we make sure that the data structure is, is correct in [sound],
讨论如何确保数据结构是正确的，
if we have multiple worker threads or processes coming in
如果我们有多个工作线程或进程进来，
and reading, writing or modifying the data structure at at the same time, right.
同时读取，写入或修改数据结构。
And this last one is going to be tricky,
最后一个比较棘手，
because we're going to care sort of two kinds of correctness in our data structures,
因为我们要关注数据结构中两种类型的正确性，
if you want to make them multi threaded,
如果你想让它们成为多线程的，
there's obviously the physical correctness of
很明显，物理的正确性，
making sure we don't have a pointer that goes nowhere
确保我们没有一个无处可去的指针，
or a page ID that that that doesn't exist, right,
或者一个不存在的页面 ID ，
if we have one one thread accessing a page,
如果我们有一个线程访问一个页面，
another thread is updating it
另一个线程正在更新它，
and that the accessing thread reads something that the guy wrote,
并且访问线程读取了这个写的东西，
but it hasn't been, you know, it's not, you know, safely committed yet or it's not saved correctly,
但它还没有安全地提交或它没有正确保存，
then we may end up, you know, falling a pointer to nowhere
然后我们可能会结束到一个无处可去的指针，
and the system would crash,
系统将崩溃，
so we have to avoid that.
所以我们必须避免这种情况。
But then there's another kind of correctness,
但是还有另一种正确性，
that we'll get to after the midterm,
我们将在期中考试后进行讨论，
at sort of the logical level
在逻辑层面上，
to make sure that if we make changes to our data structures,
以确保如果我们对数据结构进行更改，
that our own thread can see those changes,
我们自己的线程可以看到这些更改，
that it looks correct to it,
它看起来是正确的，
meaning like if my thread deletes a key from an index,
这意味着如果我的线程从索引中删除了一个键，
if I then go back in that same thread
如果我回到同一个线程，
and read, try to read that key in that index,
尝试读取该索引中的键，
I shouldn't still see it,
我不应该还看到它，
the bits may still physically be there, right,
这些比特可能还在，
because we haven't to run garbage collection
因为我们还没有运行垃圾收集，
and maybe there's a little flag that says this thing's been deleted,
也许有一个小标记，表明这个东西已经被删除了，
so physically it's still there, but logically it's not,
所以物理上它还在，但逻辑上它不在了，
we need to make sure that we don't see things we shouldn't be seeing, right.
我们要确保我们不会看到不该看到的东西。
Again, so we won't focus too much on concurrency in this week,
再说一次，本周我们不会太关注并发的事情，
but we'll cover this in more detail next week
但我们将在下周更详细地讨论这一点，
and this will be a big issue also too when we talk about concurrency control,
当我们讨论并发控制时，这将是一个大问题，
at again at the logical level, having transactions
在逻辑层面上，使用事务，
and making sure we we provide ACID guarantees,
并确保我们提供 ACID 保证，
but again, that'll be after the midterm.
但是，这将在期中之后。
All right, so today's class,
好的，所以今天的课程，
we're focusing on hash tables
我们将重点放在哈希表上，
and again, because it's a low level building blocks
因为它是一个低级别的构建块，
that we can reuse throughout the rest of the system,
我们可以在系统的其余部分中重复使用，
and again, this shouldn't be news to anyone here,
再次，这对这里的任何人来说都不是什么新闻，
a hash table is just going to be an associated array,
哈希表只是一个关联数组，
that can map keys to values.
可以将键映射到值。
You guys, okay, you guys good?
你们还好吗？
Was that?
那是什么？
The way the hash table is going to work is that,
哈希表的工作方式是，
there's going to be, it's going to be this mapping from keys to values
它将是键到值的映射，
and we're going to use a hash function,
我们将使用哈希函数，
that's going to allow us to essentially compute some offset within an array
它将允许我们计算数组中的一些偏移量，
and then it's basically reducing down the, the an arbitrary key to this integer domain,
然后基本上减少这个整型域的任意键，
that we can then jump to some, some location in our hash table
然后我们可以跳到哈希表中的某个位置，
to find the thing that we're looking for, right.
以找到我们寻找的东西。
And the, this hash function has to be able to take any possible key,
这个哈希函数必须能够接受任何可能的键，
because again, think of any column type you can define in your database system,
因为，考虑到你可以在数据库系统中定义的任何列类型，
also any, any internal metadata we have in the system itself,
还有任何我们在系统本身中拥有的内部元数据，
and we need to be able to take that,
我们需要能够，
you know, hash function needs to reduce that down to an integer.
哈希函数需要把它降低到一个整数。
So in hash table, the space complexity is going to be roughly big n or big O n,
所以在哈希表中，空间复杂性将大致为 O(n) ，
because we're going to have to store a slot for for every possible key we want to have, right,
因为我们必须为我们想要的每个可能的键存储一个槽，
the time complexity is nice,
时间复杂性很好，
because on average we're going to get O(1) lookups,
因为平均而言，我们只需要 O(1) 查找，
meaning we hash a key, jump to some location in this hash table array
这意味着我们对一个键做哈希，跳转到这个哈希表数组中的某个位置，
and then ideally there the thing that still there.
然后理想地，在那里找到仍然在那里的东西。
Or just kill it,
或者干脆杀了它，
there you go.
这就对了。
All right, so that's two kills per this semester, that's not bad.
好的，那么这学期就是两次击杀，这还不错。
So again, an average is going to be 1,
再说一次，平均是 1 ，
because it's going to be like hash,
因为这就像是哈希，
take your key, hash to some location
使用你的键，哈希到某个位置，
and then you land a thing, exactly what you're looking for,
然后你找到一个东西，就是你要找的东西，
worst case will be big O n,
最坏的情况会是 O(n) ，
because, because we'll have to deal with collisions,
因为我们将不得不处理冲突，
it may be the case,
这可能是这样的情况，
that we hash our key land in some location
我们对键的哈希在某个位置，
and then the thing we're looking for is not there
然后我们要寻找的东西不在那里，
and we got to scan along on our hash table,
我们必须扫描我们的哈希表，
we find the thing we're looking for
找到我们要找的东西，
and it may be the case that all the slots in our hash table are full
可能是哈希表中的所有槽都满了，
and we have to wrap around basically one above the one
我们必须绕过一个又一个，
where we landed the hash function,
我们位于哈希函数上，
but we had to loop around to find it, right.
但我们必须循环才能找到它。
And so the way you sort of handle this,
所以你处理这个问题的方式，
and we'll see as we go along,
我们会在接下来的过程中看到，
is you size the hash table to be roughly 2n the number of keys you expect.
你将哈希表的大小调整为大约是你期望的键数量的 2n 。
Now, you may say, okay, and Andy,
现在，你可能会说，好吧， Andy ，
how do you know, how do you know what n is,
你怎么知道 n 是什么，
well, this is, we'll get through that semester,
这是，我们会度过整个学期，
like the database system is going to try to make a decision
数据库系统会试图做出决定，
or try to predict how many keys you're going actually going to have
或者试图预测你将拥有多少键，
and size it accordingly.
并相应地调整大小。
So O(1) sounds great,
所以 O(1) 听起来很棒，
And if you're going to take an algorithms class,
如果你要上一门算法课，
this is the holy grail, you want this,
这就是圣杯，你想要这个，
you want O(1), because it's constant time,
你想要 O(1) ，因为它是恒定的时间，
but in actuality, again, in a real system,
但事实上，在一个真实的系统中，
the constants actually matter a lot,
常量实际上很重要，
so even though it's O(1),
所以即使它是 O(1) ，
you could have one hash function that maybe takes 10 milliseconds to compute,
你可以有一个哈希函数，它可能需要 10 毫秒的计算时间，
another hash function takes 1 millisecond to compute,
另一个哈希函数的计算时间为 1 毫秒，
and obviously the 1 millisecond one is meet a lot faster,
显然，1 毫秒的速度要快得多，
if you think in large scale tables like billions of keys.
如果你在数十亿个键这样的大规模表中思考。
So again, just because the algorithm complexity is, is ideal on averages 1,
所以，仅仅因为算法的复杂度是理想的，平均为 1 ，
we had to still care about the implementation
我们仍然必须关心实现，
and make sure we're as efficient as possible.
并确保我们尽可能地高效。
So let's look at the, the toy example,
让我们来看看这个玩具例子，
what a hash table looks like,
哈希表是什么样子的，
and we'll see all the problems that you can have with it,
我们会看到你可能会遇到的所有问题，
and then we'll build up this look at more sophisticated schemes,
然后我们将介绍更复杂的方案，
but are actually used in, in real world database systems.
但实际上在现实世界的数据库系统中使用。
So the easiest hash table to build is a static hash table,
所以最容易构建的哈希表是一个静态哈希表，
where you just call malloc a giant array,
你只需要调用 malloc 生成一个巨大的数组，
where you have one slot in your array for for every key I could possibly have,
对于我可能拥有的每个键，你都有一个槽在数组中，
and then to find an entry for a given key,
然后要找到给定键的条目，
you just take the, you might have the key by the number of elements you have
你可以根据你拥有的元素的数量来获得键，
and you land in some offset in the array, right,
然后你落在数组中的某个偏移量上，
so here's my offsets,
这是我的偏移量，
and then any key shows up, I know exactly where to go find it,
然后任何键出现，我知道到哪里去找它，
and you don't store the keys in this array,
你没有把键存储在这个数组中，
it's essentially just a pointer to some other location,
它本质上只是一个指向其他位置的指针，
that's going to have the key and the value together, right.
将键和值放在一起，
and the reason why you need to store the original key,
你需要存储原始键的原因是，
because since the hash may, you could have collisions,
因为哈希可能，你可能会有冲突，
which we'll get in a second,
我们稍后会了解到，
you need to check whether the key you looking that you land on through your hash table
你需要检查你通过哈希表查找的键
is actually the key you're trying to find,
是否真的是你想要找到的键，
and the value here could be a pointer to the tuple to a record ID,
这里的值可以是指向 tuple ，指向一个记录 ID 的指针，
or could there actually be some additional values,
或者可能有一些额外的值，
for our purpose today, we don't actually care.
对于我们今天的目的，我们其实并不关心。
So what are some problems with this approach?
那么，这种方法有哪些问题呢？
Yes.
是的。
He says, what if you have, what do you have,
他说，如果你有，
well, I'm assuming it's static,
好的，我假设它是静态的，
so what if you have n+1 keys,
那么，如果你有 n+1 个键，
how do you resize this thing,
你怎么调整这个东西的大小，
and you know basically, in this scenario,
基本上，在这种情况下，
you have to rehash everything,
你必须重新计算所有东西，
so that sucks.
所以这太糟糕了。
What other problems?
还有其他什么问题吗？
Yes.
是的。
Does it handle collision, What is collision?
它能处理碰撞吗，什么是碰撞？
Yes, that's correct, yes,
是的，没错，
two keys that have the same value,
两个具有相同值的键，
they're going to land in the same location in, in, in our array,
它们将落在我们数组中的相同位置，
even though they're not the same,
尽管它们不是相同的，
but I'm assuming that you know that everyone has to be unique and you can't have collisions,
但我假设每个都必须是独一无二的，你不能有冲突，
and this example doesn't handle that.
这个例子不能处理这个。
There's one more problem.
还有一个问题。
I'm assuming that the keys are unique, right,
我假设键是唯一的，
I can have key value equals one
我的键值可以等于 1 ，
and key value equals two
键值可以等于 2 ，
same key but different values,
相同的键，但值不同，
in my, my sort of toy example here, doesn't handle this, right.
我的玩具例子，不能处理这个。
So this is unrealistic again for these three assumptions.
所以，对于这三个假设，这是不现实的。
So the first one is,
所以第一个是，
you have to know all the keys ahead of time,
你必须提前知道所有的键，
in some cases, you do other cases, you don't,
在某些情况下，你知道，其他情况下，你不知道，
in the case of the buffer pool,
在缓冲池的情况下，
and then we talked about last class,
我们上一节课讨论的，
that if you assume that the, you know, the size of your buffer pool is fixed,
如果假设缓冲池的大小是固定的，
you're going to have a fixed number of frames in your buffer pool,
那么缓冲池中将有固定数量的帧，
therefore, you know the exact number of slots you need in your hash table,
这样，你直到你的哈希表中需要的确切槽数，
but if I if I build a hash table index
但是，如果我构建了一个哈希表索引，
and I keep inserting tuples,
我一直插入 tuple ，
now the number of keys is growing, as I insert new tuples.
那么当我插入新的 tuple 时，键的数量就会增加。
Every key is unique in this scenario,
在这个场景中，每个键都是唯一的，
here again, how do we need a way to handle keys that have duplicate keys,
同样，我们需要一种方法来处理具有重复键的键，
we have different values,
我们有不同的值，
got to handle that.
得处理好这件事。
And then the thing the he brought up is that,
然后他提出的事情是，
we're assuming here we have what it's called a perfect hash function,
我们假设我们这里有一个所谓的完美散列函数，
that guarantees no collisions,
它保证不会发生碰撞，
which does not exist in the real world
这在现实世界中是不存在的，
and this in the real world,
在现实世界中，
but it's basically toy [],
但这基本上是玩具[]，
no database system can actually do this,
没有数据库系统可以真正做到这一点，
because again, you need to know the key domain ahead of time, right,
因为同样，你需要提前知道键的域，
there's no magical hash function that guarantees,
没有神奇的哈希函数可以保证，
for any given key, you can generate a unique, unique hash value,
任何给定的键，你可以生成唯一的哈希值，
the way to actually implement one of those is through a hash table,
实际实现其中之一的方法是通过哈希表，
so you basically need a hash table for your hash table to do this,
所以你的哈希表基本上需要一个哈希表来实现这个，
for some systems do do that,
有些系统确实会这样做，
but not for a hash function.
但不会对哈希函数。
So we've got to be smarter,
所以我们必须变得更聪明，
and we got to make sure that,
我们必须确保，
we deal with the environment that we're operating in with databases.
我们与使用数据库操作的环境打交道。
All right, so there's two decisions we have to make
好的，所以我们必须做出两个决定，
when we run a about a hash table,
当我们运行关于哈希表时，
so someone says they have a hash table, it's sort of two parts there,
有人说哈希表有两个部分，
the hash function itself,
哈希函数本身，
that can how to map a large key space down to a finite, smaller domain,
它可以将一个大的键空间映射到一个有限的、较小的域，
based on the number of slots, I'm going to have in in my array,
根据我的数组中将要包含的槽的数量，
and there be this trade off
这里有一个权衡，
between how fast we want our hash function to be
在我们希望哈希函数的速度，
versus how likely it is that two keys, two distinct keys will collide.
与两个不同的键发生冲突的可能性之间。
What's the hash, what's the fastest hash function I could build?
我能构建的最快的哈希函数是什么？
What's that?
那是什么？
So, [], you can go faster than that,
[]，你可以比这个更快，
so he basically says,
所以他说的是，
for a given key, you spit out the same key,
对于一个给定的键，你吐出相同的键，
but if you have a string key and I got to make it an integer,
但是如果你有一个字符串键，而我要把它变成一个整数，
how do I do that?
我该怎么做？
So take the first bit,
拿出第一个位，
yeah, that would be pretty fast, too,
是的，那也会很快的，
you just can return 1, right,
你可以只返回 1 ，
that sit in the stack in a register that be super fast.
它们位于寄存器中的堆栈中，速度非常快。
It's the worst hash function in terms of collision,
就碰撞而言，这是最糟糕的哈希函数，
because everything is going to map to 1,
因为所有东西都将映射到 1 ，
but it it'll be fast.
但它会很快。
So it's this trade off trying to figure out
所以这是一种权衡试图找出，
and you sort of think the perfect hash function is the other end,
而你有点认为完美的哈希函数是另一端，
the collision rate is, is, is, is zero,
碰撞率是零，
but it's super slow,
但它非常慢，
because you have to do this extra lookup.
因为你必须进行额外的查找。
So you want something in the middle,
所以你想要中间的东西，
that's going to be fast and and have a low collision rate.
既快速又有低碰撞率。
And, and then the hashing scheme is going be
然后，哈希方案将是，
the mechanism we're going to use to handle collisions after we done our hashing
我们在完成哈希之后将用来处理冲突的机制，
and the way the trade off here is going to be again,
这里的权衡方式将是，
sort of the classic storage versus compute in computer science,
计算机科学中经典的存储与计算，
like I could, I could allocate a two terabyte hash table
比如我可以分配一个 2TB 的哈希表，
and I'm pretty, pretty unlikely going to have, I'm not likely going to have collisions
我不太可能有冲突，
for my key set is super small,
因为我的键集非常小，
but I allocated this massive hash table,
但我分配了这个巨大的哈希表，
or I can have a smaller one,
或者我可以有一个更小的，
but I'll have a lot of collisions
但我会有很多碰撞，
and therefore I have to spend more compute to handle those collisions.
因此我必须花费更多的计算来处理这些碰撞。
So again, it's trying to figure out how to do the right, get the right trade off
所以，它试图找出如何做正确的权衡，
between not over allocating,
在不过度分配，
but then also not wasting a lot of instructions to deal with with collisions.
同时也不浪费大量指令来处理碰撞之间。
All right, so today's talk,
好的，今天的演讲，
we'll talk a little bit about hash functions,
我们将稍微讨论一下哈希函数，
just to show you what the state of the art is,
只是为了向你们展示什么是最先进的，
I'm not going to say how they work
我不会说它们是如何工作的，
to tell you that they exist,
来告诉你们它们的存在，
again, we're database people,
再次，我们是数据库人，
we're not in the business of writing hash functions,
我们不是做编写哈希函数的，
we'll let other people do that for us.
我们会让别人为我们做这件事。
And then we'll talk about the sort of the classic static hashing schemes,
然后我们将讨论经典的静态哈希方案，
where, you know, the number of keys ahead of time.
在这种方案中，提前知道键的数量。
And then we'll talk about dynamic hashing schemes,
然后我们将讨论动态哈希方案，
where the hash table can actually grow and shrink,
其中哈希表可以增长和缩小，
based on the number of keys,
根据键的数量，
okay?
好的？
All right.
好的。
So again, we're not in the business of writing hash functions,
再说一次，我们不是在做编写哈希函数的，
other people that are smarter than us in this space have have done it for us,
在这个领域，其他比我们更聪明的人已经为我们做到了这个，
so we're just going to rely on them.
所以，我们将依靠它们。
Again, the basic idea of a hash functions is that,
哈希函数的基本思想是，
we have some input key,
我们有一些输入键，
any arbitrary number of bytes of any type,
任何类型的任意数量的字节，
and we need to return an integer that represents that key,
我们需要返回一个表示那个键的整数，
typically is 64 bits,
通常是 64 位，
there are 128 bit hash functions,
有 128 位的哈希函数，
but I don't think databases use those,
但我不认为数据库使用这些，
there are 32 bit hash functions as well,
还有 32 位哈希函数，
so to return an integer.
所以要返回一个整数。
So in this scheme or in, in this, in a database system,
所以在这个方案，或者在这个数据库系统中，
we don't care about any sort of protection privacy mechanisms for a hash function,
我们不关心哈希函数的任何类型的保护隐私机制，
meaning we're not going to use anything that has cryptographic guarantees,
意味着我们不会使用任何有加密保证的东西，
so we're not using SHA-256 or whatever,
所以我们没有使用 SHA-256 或其他任何东西，
like we don't, we don't care about those things,
我们不在乎这些东西，
because we're running on the inside of the system,
因为我们在系统内部运行，
it's we're not worried about leaking anything,
我们并不担心会泄露任何东西，
when we can build a hash table to do a JOIN,
当我们可以构建一个哈希表来进行 JOIN 时，
because no one on the outside of the system can see that data structure,
因为系统外部的任何人都看不到该数据结构，
so we don't care about any of those things
所以我们不关心任何这些事情，
and as a result, we can actually run a lot faster, right,
结果是，我们可以跑得更快，
SHA-256 will be really slow
SHA-256 的速度会非常慢，
versus something like like MurmurHash or XXHash.
相对于 MurmurHash 或 XXHash 之类的东西。
And as I already said before,
正如我之前说过的，
we want something that's fast and it has a low collision rate.
我们想要的是速度快、碰撞率低的东西。
So, this is just a quick, quick overview,
所以，这只是一个快速的概述，
what hash function systems are using,
了解系统使用的是什么哈希函数，
some like Postgres roll their own hash function,
有些像 Postgres 使用他们自己的哈希函数，
but a lot of the more modern systems,
但许多更现代的系统，
they're going to use something off the shelf,
他们将使用现成的东西，
like XXHash or MurmurHash or the SpookyHash.
比如 XXHash 或 MurmurHash 或 SpookyHash 。
So basically the main takeaway from this is that,
所以，从根本上说，这一点的主要结论是，
the state of art one is XXHash from Facebook,
最先进的一个是 Facebook 的 XXHash ，
with the third version, XXHash-3,
第三个版本， XXHash-3 ，
this one is shown to have the fastest performance and also the lowest collision rate,
这个版本被证明具有最快的性能和最低的冲突率，
there are some systems that use CRC-32 or 64 for hashing integers,
有一些系统使用 CRC-32 或 64 来哈希整数，
because it would actually CPU instructions in x86 that do that in a few number of cycles,
因为 x86 中的 CPU 指令会在几个周期内完成它，
there are some systems that do that,
有一些系统做这个，
but in terms of random strings, you typically want to use this,
但在随机字符串方面，你通常希望使用这个，
so MurmurHash is [],
MurmurHash 是[]，
because it was MurmurHash was written by this [random dude] on the Internet,
因为 MurmurHash 是由一个[随机的家伙]在互联网上写的，
he had a good, fast general purpose hash function,
他有一个好的、快速的通用哈希函数，
Google took that and made CityHash by forking it,
Google 采用它，并通过 fork 做了 CityHash ，
and then they have a newer version,
然后他们有了一个更新的版本，
we call it FarmHash,
我们称之为 FarmHash ，
that has even better collision rates,
它的有更好的碰撞率，
there's, there's a bunch of different hash functions out there,
有很多不同的哈希函数，
but XXHash-3 is what you want to use.
但是 XXHash-3 是你想要使用的。
And so there's a bunch of these repositories on Github,
GitHub 上有一堆这样的存储库，
or people I've written basically [] or benchmarks to,
或者人们[]或基准，
to run all possible hash functions that are out there
运行所有可能的哈希函数，
and see what their collision rate is,
看看它们的碰撞率是多少，
see what the performance is,
看看性能是什么，
so this is this Mhasher SMhasher,
这个是 SMhasher ，
there's another one written by the MurmurHash guy
这是另一个 MurmurHash 的人写的，
and there's another one that's a fork at this,
还有一个是这个方面的 fork ，
that's only [] all the cryptography stuff,
这只是[]所有密码学的东西，
but for this repository here,
但对于这里的存储库，
they have this nice summary here,
他们在这里有一个很好的总结，
that says these are the ones that work the best and have good collision rates,
说这些是工作最好的，并且有很好的碰撞率，
and then the top one here is XXHash-3, the Facebook one.
然后这里最上面的是 XXHash-3 ， Facebook 的那个。
So again, we don't care,
所以，我们并不关系，
it's a hash function, keys in, integer out,
这是一个哈希函数，输入键，输出整型，
we'll just use whatever they have.
我们将使用他们给出的任何东西。
And then there's the full list of all the different hash functions,
然后这是所有不同哈希函数的完整列表，
some are tailored to ARM,
有些是为 ARM 量身定制的，
some are tailored x86 or whatever
有些是为 x86 量身定制的，或任何（CPU），
you can, you can get, you know, more low level details based on the environment,
你可以根据环境获得更多的低级别细节，
but XXHash3 is going to be a good default choice.
但 XXHash3 将是一个很好的默认选择。
All right, so now.
好的，现在。
Assuming, assuming running XXHash3,
假设运行 XXHash3 ，
we want to talk about what the hash table is going to look like
我们想讨论一下哈希表是什么样子的，
and how do we handle collisions.
以及如何处理碰撞。
So for this lecture, I'm going to focus on the two most common ones,
所以在这节课上，我将集中讨论两个最常见的问题，
but number one is actually going to be the most common one of all the systems,
但第一个是所有系统中最常见的一个，
linear probe hashing,
线性探测哈希，
it's the simplest,
这是最简单的，
and it seems kind of brain dead in some ways,
在某些方面，它似乎有点脑残，
but because it's so simple, it is actually the fastest, right.
但因为它是如此简单，它实际上是最快的。
And then Cuckoo hashing is a variant of this,
而 Cuckoo 哈希是它的一个变体，
that basically does multiple hash functions.
它基本上是执行多个哈希函数。
So there's a bunch of other techniques,
所以还有很多其他的技术，
Robin Hood hashing, Hopscotch hashing,
Robin Hood 哈希， Hopscotch 哈希，
Swiss Tables from Google,
来自 Google 的 Swiss 表，
we won't cover that in this semester,
这学期我们不会讲这些，
but if you take the advanced class,
但如果你选了高级课程，
we will cover those things.
我们会讲这些内容。
And I would say that, the current research basically shows that,
我要说的是，目前的研究基本上表明，
the Linear Probe stuff and the Swiss Tables are the fastest ones,
线性探测的东西和 Swiss 表是最快的，
all these extra fancy versions are,
所有这些额外的花式版本是，
as they try to be, they try to be more performance,
他们试图提高性能，
because they avoid having to spend longer time looking for for keys
因为他们避免了更长的寻找键的时间，
by moving things around, when when you insert,
当插入时，移动东西时，
but all that work of moving things around is is a performance penalty
但是所有移动东西的工作都是性能损失，
and you're better off just doing the naive thing in your hashing.
你最好在哈希中做一些简单的事情。
This question, there's a reason why we're not talking about chain hashing,
这个问题，我们不讨论链哈希的原因，
because that's dynamic, that'll be next,
因为它是动态的，它是下一个，
chain hashing can grow, this is fixed size,
链哈希可以增长，这个是固定大小，
that we'll cover that later this semester or later this class,
我们会在这学期，这节课的晚些时候讲到，
these are all static hashing schemes.
这些都是静态哈希方案。
There's variations of linear probing, probing,
有各种各样的线性探测，
let's keep it simple.
让我们简单一点。
All right, so Linear Probe hashing is really simple,
好的，所以线性探测哈希很简单，
it's a giant array of slots
它是一个巨大的 slot 数组，
and we're going to hash into it,
我们要哈希到它，
if we insert, we hash into it,
如果我们插入，我们会哈希到它，
if the slot is free,
如果 slot 是空的，
we insert the thing we're looking for,
我们就插入我们要找的东西，
if the slot is not free,
如果 slot 不是空的，
we just look at the next slot and insert there if we can,
我们只需查看下一个 slot 并插入到那里，
or we keep looking until we have a free slot,
或者我们继续寻找，直到我们有一个空闲的 slot ，
potentially wrapping around,
可能会环绕，
until we find a free location.
直到我们找到一个空闲的地方。
And then if we loop back around
然后如果我们循环回来，
and realize we're at the slot where we started that,
意识到我们在开始的 slot ，
then we know the hash table is full
那么我们知道哈希表是满的，
and we have to and you know abort it,
我们必须中止它，
double the size and rehash everything,
加倍大小，重新哈希所有东西，
it's a simple way to grow it, right.
这是一种简单的增长方式。
So the state, our implementation for this or one state is this [] thing from, from Google,
所以我们对这个的实现来自 Google ，
and it's the flat_hash, flat_hash_map type or data structure,
它是 flat_hash_map 类型或数据结构，
and they have pretty good documentation to describe actually how it works,
他们有非常好的文档来描述它是如何工作的，
and some of the optimizations they do will cover.
并且他们所做的一些优化将涵盖在内。
So this is sometimes called open addressing, open addressing hashing,
所以这有时被称为开放寻址哈希，
because the idea is that it,
因为它的思想是，
there's no guarantee that for a given key,
不能保证对于给定的键，
it's going to always be in the same address or same location in the slot,
它将始终位于 slot 中的相同地址或相同位置，
depending on what, what, what got inserted before it,
取决于在它之前插入了什么，
it may, it may get moved around, right.
它可能会移来移去。
If you get a dictionary in Python,
如果你得到一个 Python 的字典，
this is essentially what you're getting as well.
这基本上也是你要得到的东西。
So let's see how it works.
所以让我们来看看它是如何工作的。
So say we want to insert key A, right,
假设我们想要插入键 A ，
so we hash it,
所以我们对它进行哈希，
mod by the number of slots that we have
根据我们拥有的 slot 的数量取模，
and then we hit land this a location here,
然后我们到达这个位置，
so that we insert our key along the value together, right,
这样我们就可以插入键，和值一起，
again, the reason why we need the key is because,
再次，我们需要键的原因是，
if we go to a lookup again for looking for A,
如果我们再次查找 A ，
we need, we hash to the same location,
我们需要哈希到相同的位置，
but now we got to do an equality check
但现在我们必须做一个相等检查，
to see whether the key that we're looking for is the key in in a given slot.
看看我们正在寻找的键是否是给定 slot 中的键。
Same thing, so if you want to hash B,
一样的东西，如果你想要对 B 进行哈希，
same thing, hash here mod by the number of slots,
同样的事情，在这里哈希，对 slot 的数量取模，
we end up here and we sort at the top.
我们最终在这里，排在顶部。
So now we want to insert C,
所以现在我们要插入 C ，
so we hash C,
所以我们哈希 C ，
it lands to the same location where A is,
它到达 A 所在的相同位置，
but that slot is occupied,
但是那个 slot 被占用了，
so we can't insert it there,
所以我们不能把它插入到那里，
so we just follow down to the next slot
所以我们只需往下走到下一个 slot ，
and insert our key there, right.
然后在那里插入我们的键。
Same thing with D,
对于 D 也是同样的事情，
D once to go where C is,
一旦 D 去到 C 所在的地方，
it can't, because that slot occupied,
它就不能，因为那个 slot 被占用了，
so it just moves down to the next one and inserts it there.
所以它向下移动到下一个，然后插入到那里。
And we just keep going down for all the other keys we want to store, right.
我们继续，对于我们想要存储的所有其他键。
And in this case here,
在这种情况下，
if, say, if F, this space was occupied,
假设 F 这个空间被占用了，
F kind of wrapped around, start at the beginning and insert at the top,
F 绕回，从顶部开始，插入到顶部，
think of it as a giant circular buffer.
把它想象成一个巨大的圆形缓冲区。
Pretty simple, right?
很简单，对吧？
What are some potential problems with this?
这有哪些潜在的问题？
He says deletion sucks,
他说，删除很糟糕，
says you lose the whole chain,
意味着你失去了整个链，
what do you mean?
你是什么意思？
Right, so he says,
好的，所以他说，
I don't think all the slides ahead of time,
我不认为所有的幻灯片都提前了，
what happens, what happens if you delete C?
如果删除 C ，会发生什么情况？
So delete C, we hash it,
所以删除 C ，我们对它进行哈希，
we land where A is, right,
我们落在 A 所在的地方，
now we do the equality check to see does A equal C,
现在我们做相等检查，看看 C 是否等于 A ，
no, so we know that's not the key we're looking for
不，所以我们知道这不是我们要找的键，
and then we keep going
然后我们继续前进，
until we find empty slot or the key we're looking for,
直到我们找到空的 slot 或我们要找的键，
so in this case here,
在这种情况下，
after jumping down, we find C
在跳下之后，我们找到 C ，
and now we need to delete it,
现在我们需要删除它，
but now we have an empty space, as he said,
但现在我们有一个空的空间，就像他说的，
so if I try to go do a lookup on something like D,
所以如果我试着去查找 D ，
D is going to hash to this empty spot,
D 会哈希到这个空的地方，
and it's going to say, oh well, nothing is here, right,
它会说，好的，这里什么都没有，
but it really is, you know, it's the next slot down,
但它真的是，在下一个 slot ，
but because the way the protocol works, the scheme works,
但因为协议的工作方式，方案的工作方式，
if I see an empty slot, then I know I'm done, right.
如果我看到一个空的 slot ，我就知道我完成了，
So what's one way to handle this?
那么，处理这一问题的一种方法是什么？
Gravestone, tombstone, that's one approach, yes,
墓碑，这是一种方法，是的，
we'll get it there,
我们会到那里，
which that is the correct answer.
这就是正确的答案。
So you could do this,
所以你可以这样做，
you could just rehash, move up, right,
你可以重新哈希，向上移动，
is that a good idea or a bad idea,
这是个好主意还是坏主意，
well, clearly it's a bad idea,
显然这是个坏主意，
because I said no one does this,
因为我说过没人会这么做，
but why is it a bad idea?
但为什么这是个坏主意呢？
Move everything,
移动所有东西，
again, think huge, a billion keys,
想象大一点，十亿个键，
I going to go rehash everyone that be terrible, right,
我要去重新哈希每一个，那是很糟糕的，
so it's super expensive and no one does this.
所以它非常昂贵，没有人做这个。
Skipping through this, right.
跳过这个。
So yeah, this is not the sense,
所以，是的，这没有道理，
you don't want to do this.
你不想做这个。
The correct solution is what he was saying is what it's called a tombstone,
正确的答案是他说的是墓碑，
and the idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
I delete C,
我删除 C ，
but instead, again, instead of setting it as empty,
但是不是将其设置为空，
I'm gonna put a little marker here,
我将在这里放一个小标记，
to say this slot,
表示这个 slot ，
there was a key here and now it's been deleted.
曾经有一个键在这里，现在它被删除了。
So that way,
这样的话，
if anybody comes along like doing a lookup in D,
如果有人过来，比如，做一个查找 D ，
it sees the tombstone
它看到墓碑，
and says, well, it's not empty,
说，嗯，它不是空的，
something was here,
有东西曾经在这里，
but there's nothing here that I'm looking for,
但这里没有我要找的东西，
so let me, let me look down and keep scanning along
所以让我往下看，继续扫描，
until I find the thing I'm looking for, right.
直到我找到我要找的东西。
So you can reuse these,
所以你可以重复使用这些，
you can reuse the slot with the marker of the tombstone for new keys,
你可以重新使用带有墓碑标记的 slot 给新的键，
you just insert over top of it
你只需要在它上面插入，
and that doesn't break the flow or break anything else in, in the hash table, right.
这不会打破流程或哈希表中任何内容。
Now, maybe the case you want to periodically run a garbage collection,
现在，也许你想定期地运行一个垃圾收集，
because you can start accumulating much of these tombstones
因为你可以开始积累大量的这些墓碑，
and it's just wasted space,
那是在浪费空间，
if you're not reusing them,
如果你不重复使用它们，
but for our purposes, we can ignore that.
但是对于我们的目的，我们可以忽略它。
So I want to put say G,
所以我想放入 G ，
G can go right here
G 可以在这里，
and that's fine.
这是可以的。
Now, I'm not going, not going to discuss this too much details,
现在，我不打算讨论太多的细节，
but there is a challenge though,
但是有一个挑战，
how you actually want to represent these tombstones,
你实际上如何表示这些墓碑，
and also represent something that is empty,
同时也表示了一种空的东西，
and potentially also represent that I have a null key,
也可能表示我有一个 null 键，
which you can do in a database system, right.
这是你可以在数据库系统中做的。
So we could do the trick we talked about before with slotted pages,
所以，我们可以使用我们之前讨论过的 slotted pages 的技巧，
where we could have a bitmap in front of at the top of every head or every page in our hash table,
我们可以在哈希表中的每个头部或每个页面的顶部前面放置一个 bitmap ，
I'm not showing the division here between pages,
我没有在这里显示页面之间的划分，
but think of like,
但是考虑，
for simplicity, every page is to these slots,
简单起见，每个页面都是这些 slot ，
so in the header of that page,
所以在页面的头部中，
I could keep track of like,
我可以跟踪，
okay, here's the slots that are empty,
好的，这里是空的 slot ，
here's the slots that are null,
这里是 null slot ，
or here's the slots that are, that are, that are marked with the tombstone.
或者这里是有墓碑标记的 slot 。
So I need some additional metadata to keep track of these things,
所以我需要一些额外的元数据来跟踪这些事情，
and you obviously don't want to do it on a per key basis,
你显然不想在每个键的基础上这样做，
because, that could mess up with the alignment of things waste space.
因为，这可能会扰乱事物的排列方式，浪费空间。
So the other thing we got to deal with now is non-unique keys.
我们现在要处理的另一件事是非唯一键。
All right.
好的。
So there's two approaches to do this.
所以，有两种方法可以做到这个。
One is that,
其中之一是，
instead of storing the value in our giant hash array, array, along with the keys,
不是将值与键一起存储在我们的大型哈希数组中，
instead, the value would just be a pointer, like a page ID,
取而代之的是，该值只是一个指针，比如页面 ID ，
to some other location that will store my list of keys, sorry list of values, right,
到每个其他未知，存储我的键列表，抱歉，值列表，
so for the key XYZ,
所以对于键 XYZ ，
there's a pointer to some, basically a linked list,
有一个指针指向一个链表，
that has all the possible values,
它有所有可能的值，
and then for the other key, the same thing.
然后对于另一个键，相同的东西。
What's nice about this is because,
这样做的好处是，
as I insert new keys, insert duplic keys over over again,
当我一次又一次地插入新键、重复键时，
I'm not really changing the main hash table,
我并没有改变主哈希表，
I'm sort of appending to this sort of link list,
我在追加到这个链表，
it's like the chain hash table that he talked about before
这就像他之前谈到的链哈希表，
or he asked about before,
或者之前他问到的，
we get in a second.
我们稍后会讨论到。
The more common approach is to store redundant keys together, right,
更常见的方法是将冗余键存储在一起，
and again, this doesn't break the open addressing of linear probe hashing scheme
这并没有打破线性探测哈希方案的开放寻址，
is that I'm always hash the key,
我总是哈希键，
I landed on location
我落在一个地点，
and I find a, you know, I just find a free slot
我找到一个空的 slot ，
and the thing I'm looking for.
和我要找的东西。
This does make it a little bit more tricky,
这确实使它变得有点棘手，
when you do lookups,
当你查找，
like give me all, give me all the keys of XYZ, key value pairs,
比如给我所有 XYZ 的键，键值对，
because now I got, I know, like I got to keep, I got to keep scanning
因为现在我必须继续扫描，
until I find an empty location, empty slot,
直到我找到一个空的位置，空的 slot ，
to know that I'm not going to see XYZ ever again,
知道我再也见不到 XYZ 了，
whereas in the first, the first scenario,
而在第一个场景中，
I find XYZ in my hash table,
我在哈希表中找到 XYZ ，
then I land follow the pointer to the list of values
然后沿着指向值列表的指针，
and I know that's all the possible values I could have for that given key, right.
我知道这就是我可以为给定键提供的所有可能值。
But for simplicity reasons,
但为了简单起见，
instead I having't maintained the sort of separate linked list for non-unique keys
我没有为非唯一键维护单独的链表，
and and the the non, the the inline version for, for for unique keys,
以及对于唯一键的内联版本，
most systems use the redundant key approach,
大多数系统使用冗余键方法，
because you don't have to multiple implement implementations.
因为你不需要多重实现。
Yes.
是的
Your question is, how would you differentiate between?
你的问题是，你如何区分？
So his question is,
所以他的问题是，
how would you differentiate update a value versus an insert of a value,
你如何区分更新一个值，而不是插入一个值，
yeah, for hash tables, you really don't do updates,
是的，对于哈希表，你不应该做更新，
it would be a delete followed by an insert, right.
它应该是先删除后插入。
And of course, now the tricky thing is,
当然，现在棘手的事情是，
if I want to delete key XYZ with value2,
如果我想删除键 XYZ 值是 value2 ，
I, if I want to delete one of these,
如果我想删除其中一个，
I have to know the value, make sure that one,
我必须知道它的值，确保是那个，
may not be what I want.
可能不是我想要的。
The question if you have,
问题是，如果你有，
so if you have a key with multiple values,
如果你有一个键有多个值，
you just hash the entire tuple,
你只需要哈希整个 tuple ，
what do you mean by that?
你说的是什么意思？
Yeah, so like,
是的，所以就像，
yeah, so statement is like,
是的，所以声明就像，
if I'm looking for if I'm looking for exact match,
如果我在寻找完全匹配，
in that case, like I don't need the hash table,
在这种情况下，我不需要哈希表，
because if I have,
因为如果我有，
but like if I'm trying to remove it from the data structure,
但是如果我试图从数据结构中删除它，
like this exact, like key value pair, right,
就像这个完全匹配键值对，
then you basically, and you, you,
然后你基本上，
you need to find that exact pair,
你需要找到确切的对，
you need to have it time
你需要有时间，
and just maintaining the data structure.
只是维护数据结构。
The question is why, Why do this,
问题是为什么要这么做，
so like, if I'm doing a JOIN,
如果我做一个 JOIN ，
the relationship between the two join tables is that,
两个连接表之间的关系是，
one side might not be unique, right,
一边可能不是唯一的，
so I need to have this.
所以我需要这个。
And so I want to get all of the,
所以我想得到所有的，
you have basically an iterator says,
你基本上有一个迭代器，
give me all the values for key equals XYZ
给我 key 等于 XYZ 的所有值，
and spitting this things out as I'm as I'm traversing the hash table,
然后在我遍历哈希表的时候把这些东西吐出来，
because I'm doing the JOIN.
因为我在做 JOIN 。
Yes.
是的。
His question is,
他的问题是，
would you rehash,
你会不会重新哈希，
when it's completely for 80% full,
当它 80% 满的时候，
so the different systems have different,
所以不同的系统有不同的，
there's like a threshold would say,
比如有一个阈值，
if I go above this,
如果我超过这个，
I know I'm gonna overflow or run out of space,
我知道我会溢出或用完空间，
I go ahead and trigger a rehash.
我就去触发一个重新哈希，
Yeah, point, yes,
是的，观点是对的，
like the you get closer to that worst case scenario,
你越来越接近最坏的情况，
where like if it gets, it starts to get full,
比如如果它开始变满，
so rather than waiting to it's like 100% full,
所以，不是等待它 100% 满了，
maybe go to 80%, because though,
可能达到 80% ，因为，
it's better off to pay the penalty to resize the hash table,
最后承担惩罚来调整哈希表的大小，
which is doubling you,
变为两倍，
so resize hash table is double the size of it,
重新调真大小哈希是两倍它的大小，
go through all your keys
通过你所有的键，
and rehash them and put them into the new hash table
对它们进行重新哈希，放入新的哈希表中，
and then throw away the old one,
然后丢弃旧的，
that's not, that's expensive,
这是很昂贵的，
if it's a large hash table,
如果它是一个大的哈希表，
so, but there's a tradeoff of,
但是有一个权衡，
like, okay, if I'm at 80% full,
比如，好的，如果我有 80% 满，
I'd rather pay that penalty to double the size
我宁愿承担惩罚来增加一倍的大小，
rather than all the additional operations I need to do
而不是所有我需要做的额外操作，
spend a long time searching through,
需要花费很长时间进行搜索，
there's no, there's no one answer.
没有一个统一答案。
But that's, that's why there's a, there's a, there's usually a tunable threshold,
但是，通常有一个可调的阈值，
whether or not they expose, expose that to you
无论他们是否向你公开，
as like a user of the database system,
作为数据库系统的用户，
it depends on the implementation,
这取决于实现，
but there usually a threshold to say,
但通常有一个阈值说明，
when do you want to go ahead and resize.
你希望在什么时候继续并调整大小。
Okay, so some other optimizations we can do.
好的，我们还可以做一些其他的优化。
That one is you could have different hash table implementations,
一个是你可以有不同的哈希表实现，
that have these different mechanisms or like, you know, decisions
有这些不同的机制，或者决策，
about when to split, how to store things and what not,
关于何时拆分，如何存储东西，等等，
based on the data type you're storing.
基于你存储的数据类型。
So an obvious thing would be like,
所以一个显而易见的事情是，
if I have, I want to be hash tables that support string keys,
如果我想要的是支持字符串键的哈希表，
if my strings are very small,
如果我的字符串非常小，
like 64 bits 64 bits or 64 bytes or 64 bits or bytes less,
比如 64 位或 64 字节或更少，
they might store that inline my hash table,
它们可能会存储我的内联哈希表中，
but if it's a really large string,
但如果它是一个非常大的字符串，
I don't want to store that in my hash table,
我不想将其存储在我的哈希表中，
maybe I just want to have a pointer to the actual string itself,
也许我只想有一个指向实际字符串本身的指针，
so now I can have a 64 bit pointer,
所以现在我可以有一个 64 位的指针，
but now it's going to be expensive to do that lookup
但现在，进行查找成本将会很高，
to see whether I have a match,
查看是否有匹配，
so maybe I actually want to store the hash of that string
可能我真的希望将该字符串的哈希
as part of the key in my hash table
作为键的一部分存储在哈希表中，
to avoid having to do that lookup, right.
以避免进行那种查找，
We talked about storing the metadata,
我们讨论了存储元数据，
like as something a tombstone or something a null value or a or an empty slot,
比如墓碑，或者空值，或者空 slot ，
you could store that in the page header,
你可以将其存储在页头中，
because now you have a bunch of packed bits,
因为现在你有一堆打包的位，
you'd actually store that in the entire hash table itself, right.
你会将其存储在整个哈希表本身中。
So the, the Google HashMap does this,
所以， Google 的 HashMap 做到了这个，
where they have a separate hash table, just for the metadata,
他们有一个单独的哈希表，专门用于元数据，
that's much smaller and compact,
它更小、更紧凑，
you do a lookup on that,
你在它上面进行查找，
to tell you what is the thing you're about to go look up in the the real hash table,
告诉你要在真正的哈希表中查找的是什么，
is that thing you know, null or, or, or empty or not.
那个东西是否是空值或空的。
And then this one is interesting,
然后这个很有趣，
this one comes from Clickhouse,
这一个来自 Clickhouse ，
the OLAP system that came out of the index in Russia,
这是俄罗斯的一种基于索引的 OLAP 的系统，
so they talk about how they want to be,
所以他们谈论他们想要成为什么样子，
since it's so expensive to allocate the memory for a hash table,
因为为哈希表分配内存是如此昂贵，
you don't want to just, you know, allocate a bunch of memory,
你不会想要分配一堆内存，
use it once and then throw it away,
使用一次，然后扔掉，
which you actually want to just reuse that, that memory over and over again,
你想要一次又一次地重复使用那个内存，
but you need a fast way to clear it out,
但你需要一种快速的方法来清理它，
so instead of going through and marking all the slots as deleted,
所以，不是遍历并将所有 slot 标记为已删除，
you just maintain a version counter, a version ID,
你只需维护一个版本计数器，版本 ID ，
and whenever you say I want to delete the contents of this table,
每当你说我想删除该表的内容时，
you just increment that version counter on the table,
你只需递增该表上的版本计数器，
and then now any lookup you do inside of a slot inside that table,
现在，如果你在该表内的插槽中执行的任何查找，
if the version IDs don't match,
如果版本 ID 不匹配，
then if the slot version number is less than the table version number,
如果 slot 版本号小于表版本号，
then you know it's been deleted
你知道它已经被删除，
and you can ignore everything in there
你可以忽略其中的所有内容，
and that clears it out and then you increment the version ID.
这将清除它，然后递增版本 ID 。
So there a bunch of different tricks you can do in different scenarios
所以，你可以在不同的场景中使用一系列不同的技巧
to make these things run more efficiently
来使这些事情更高效地运行，
and the various systems do different things,
不同的系统做不同的事情，
Clickhouse, in my opinion,
Clickhouse ，在我看来，
there's, that link there will take you to the blog article,
那个链接可以把你带到博客文章，
they claim they have 30 different implementations of hash tables,
他们声称他们有 30 种不同的哈希表实现，
a lot of it templateized based in C++, based on the data type,
其中很多都是基于 C++ 模板化的，基于数据类型，
and they do a bunch of compiler tricks
他们做了一系列的编译器技巧，
to, to remove code you don't need,
来删除你不需要的代码，
if you know, like something cannot be null
如果你知道，比如某个东西不能为空，
or is a string of certain size,
或者是一个特定大小的字符串，
they probably, in my opinion, of all the source systems I looked at,
在我看来，在我研究的所有源系统中，
they're probably the most sophisticated ones,
它们可能是最复杂的，
that have the most sophisticated hash tables.
拥有最复杂的哈希表。
All right, so one variant of linear, linear probe hashing is a technique called Cuckoo hashing.
好的，线性探测哈希的一种变体是一种被称为 Cuckoo 哈希的技术。
And the idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
instead of having a single hash function,
不是只有一个哈希函数，
to do a look up to one location in my, in my hash table,
在我的哈希表中查找一个位置，
what if I had multiple hash functions
如果我有多个哈希函数，
and I hash up multiple locations
并且我哈希了多个位置，
and I find whatever one has a free slot,
我找到了任何一个有空闲 slot 的位置，
and I use that one,
我就用那个，
instead of having to scan through now,
而不是必须扫描，
until I find a free slot for my key.
直到我为键找到一个空闲的 slot 。
So this is going to guarantee that all my lookup and deletions will be O(1),
所以这将保证我所有的查找和删除都是 O(1) ，
because no matter how many hash functions I have,
因为不管我有多少哈希函数，
you know, I don't have to scan through,
我不需要扫一遍，
I'm going to land at some location in my, in my HashMap or my hash table,
我会落在我的 HashMap 或哈希表中的某个位置，
that has the data that I'm looking for,
那里有我正在寻找的数据，
or it doesn't exist,
或者它不存在，
insert is going to be more expensive,
插入将会更昂贵，
because we'll see it in a second,
因为，我们很快就会看到它，
you may have to start moving things around and reorganizing stuff.
你可能不得不开始移动东西，重新组织东西。
So there's only one system I know that does Cuckoo hashing,
据我所知，只有一个系统做了 Cuckoo 哈希，
that publicly talks about it,
公开谈论它，
and that's this overlap accelerator from IBM called BLU B L U,
这是来自 IBM 的重叠加速器叫做 BLU, B L U ，
and in their paper,
在他们的论文中，
they talk about how they make heavy use of of Cuckoo hashing.
他们谈到了是如何大量使用 Cuckoo 哈希的。
And as far as, you know,
根据当前所知，
the best open-source implementation of a Cuckoo hash table is actually
Cuckoo 哈希表最好的开源实现是，
from David Anderson from CMU,
来自 CMU 的 David Anderson ，
I think Google, said, David claims Google uses a lot of it.
我认为 Google ， David 声称 Google 大量使用了它。
And so the name has to do, the Cuckoo has to do with.
所以名字， Cuckoo 。
Okay, it send by Google that, yeah.
好的， Google 发送的。
So.
所以。
So the name Cuckoo has to do with this bird,
所以， Cuckoo 这个名字与这种鸟有关，
where they lay their eggs, they can lay their eggs in another bird's nest, right,
它们可以把蛋下到另一个鸟巢里，
and so the idea is,
所以这个想法是，
my key may end up, may end up [stealing] somebody else's slot in my hash table,
我的键可能最终会[窃取]别人在我的哈希表中的位置，
if I try to go there and they're using it.
如果我试图去那里，而他们正在使用它。
So let's see examples.
让我们来看一些例子。
So say we have, again, we have a simple hash table,
假设我们有一个简单的哈希表，
but now anytime we do an operation,
但现在任何时候我们做一个操作，
we're going to have two hash functions,
我们都会有两个哈希函数，
so it's going to be the same hash function implementation that we talked about before,
所以这将是我们之前讨论的相同的哈希函数实现，
like XXHash, MurmurHash, SpookyHash, it doesn't matter,
比如 XXHash MurmurHash SpookyHash ，这无关紧要，
but we'll just give it a different seed to the hash function,
但我们给哈希函数一个不同的种子，
that guarantees for a given key, it doesn't guarantee,
保证对于给定的键，它并不保证，
but it's very likely that that for a given key,
但很可能对于给定的键，
it's going, it's going to produce two different hash values.
它将产生两个不同的哈希值。
So I hash A,
所以我哈希 A ，
and I have these two locations here,
这里有两个位置，
so at the very beginning,
所以一开始，
my hash table is empty,
我的哈希表是空的，
so I can either flip a coin or pick the first one, it doesn't matter,
所以我可以抛硬币，也可以挑第一个，这都无关紧要，
and so I'll decide that for inserting A,
所以我决定，对于插入 A ，
it goes in the first slot here,
它在这里的第一个 slot ，
now I want to put B in,
现在我想把 b 放进去，
and so the first hash function hash to where A is,
所以第一个哈希函数哈希 A 的位置，
the second hash function goes to an empty slot,
第二个哈希函数是空的 slot ，
so because the other one is occupied,
因为另一个是空的，
I'm going to always choose the empty one
所以我会一直选择空的，
and I'll put B at the top like that,
我会把 B 放在最上面，
Now where things get tricky is that,
现在事情变得棘手的是，
we have multiple, two hash functions or multiple hash functions hash to two locations that both have,
我们有两个哈希函数或多个哈希函数哈希到两个位置，
that are both are being occupied,
这两个位置都被占用，
so in this case here,
所以在这种情况下，
for whatever, you know, whatever protocol, whatever scheme we want to use,
不管什么，不管我们想用什么协议，什么方案，
say we can flip a coin, we decide we want to evict B,
比如说我们可以抛硬币，我们决定驱逐 B ，
so we'll go ahead and bash B on the head,
所以我们继续，敲击 B 的头部，
take its location, put C in there,
拿取它的位置，把 C 放进去，
but now we now we got to put B back in,
但是现在我们要把 B 放回去，
so because B landed on this using the second hash function,
因为 B 落在这里，使用了第二个哈希函数，
after we, after we take it out and put it back in,
在我们将其取出并放回之后，
we use the first hash function,
我们使用第一个哈希函数，
but then that takes us to the location where A is located,
但这就把我们带到了 A 所在的位置，
so B is allowed to steal from A,
所以 B 被允许从 A 窃取，
so B goes there, A comes out,
所以 B 去了那里， A 出来了，
we hash A with a second hash function,
我们用第二个哈希函数对 A 进行哈希，
and then we land to another location.
然后我们落到另一个位置。
And again, just like before in linear probe hashing,
同样，就像之前的线性探测哈希一样，
you need to keep track of, if you're stuck in a loop, right,
你需要跟踪你是否被困在循环中，
so you just got to keep track is,
所以你要跟踪的是，
this is the key, I'm putting in the same key,
这是键，我把同样的键放进去，
I try to first put in the very beginning
我试着首先放在最开始的地方，
and I've I've just loop back around and I'm stuck in an infinite loop
我循环回来，我被困在无限循环中，
and therefore I need to abort,
因此我需要放弃，
double the size of the hash table and rehash everything.
两倍哈希表的大小，并重新哈希所有内容。
So now when I want to do a lookup on B,
所以现在当我想要查找 B 时，
I take B, hash it twice
我使用 B ，对它进行两次哈希，
and I get two different locations
我得到了两个不同的位置，
and now I do my check to see,
现在我检查一下，
is the key stored in this slot the key I'm looking for,
存放在这个 slot 中的键是否是我要找的键，
if yes, then I have the thing I'm looking for.
如果是，那么我就有我要找的东西了。
Again now, and I don't need to do that linear probe scanning or looking for an empty slot,
现在，我不需要执行线性探测扫描，或者查找空的 slot ，
key I'm looking for,
我在查找的键，
because I'm guaranteed,
因为我可以保证，
either the key is going to be there after hashing
哈希之后，要么键就在那里，
or does not exist in the table.
要么不在表中。
This is a good idea or bad idea?
这是个好主意还是坏主意？
He said it seems like there would be more collisions.
他说，看起来会有更多的碰撞。
Well, no, right, because if,
好的，不，因为如果，
well, so like,
嗯，就像这样，
there's trade offs, right,
这是有取舍的，
yes, could be more collisions,
是的，可能会有更多的碰撞，
but like, at least in linear probe hashing,
但是，至少在线性探测散列中，
you're guaranteed to always put something in there, right,
你保证总是会放一些东西在里面，
it may be in the worst slot,
它可能在最糟糕的 slot ，
maybe the slot right above the one you try to go into
也许就在你试图进入的那个 slot 的正上方，
and you loop back around,
然后你循环回来，
but at least if there's a free slot, you'll get it.
但至少如果有空的 slot ，你就会得到它。
Yes.
好的。
Yeah, he's absolutely right,
是的，他说的完全正确，
so this is doing random IOs,
这是在做随机 IO ，
because I'm jumping around,
因为我在跳来跳去，
the hash table is essentially random IOs,
哈希表本质上是随机 IO ，
but once I land somewhere, doing a random lookup,
但是一旦我落在某个地方，执行随机查找，
then a sequential scan,
那么就是顺序 IO 了，
this is always random, right.
这永远是随机的。
I mean, that's the life.
我是说，这就是生活。
It's impressive, yeah,
令人印象深刻，
okay. I I mean, you're a good DJ, it's not,
好的，我是说，你是个好 DJ ，
and you do databases, that makes sense, right?
你做的数据库，这是有意义的，对吧？
Yeah, all right, congrats.
好的，祝贺你。
So your question was?
所以你的问题是？
Yeah, so his question is,
是的，所以他的问题是，
is it possible to parallelize the access to different locations?
有没有可能并行通往不同位置的访问？
Yes, you could do that,
是的，你可以这么做，
like there's two different ways to parallelize,
有两种不同的并行方式，
we'll eventually get to there,
我们最终会做到这个，
like you can have multiple threads
比如你可以有多个线程
or single threads, but do vectorized instructions, SIMD instructions, like,
或单个线程做向量化指令， SIMD 指令，
and for SIMD, this won't,
对于 SIMD 来说，这不会，
you could do this,
你可以这样做，
but it requires you moving data around a bit much,
但它需要你移动数据的次数有点多，
because you have to make sure things aligned,
因为你必须确保数据保持对齐，
but,
但是，
so you may introduce with a single thread with vectorized instructions,
所以，你可以引入带有向量化指令的单个线程，
I know there's techniques exist,
我知道有技术存在，
I don't know about Cuckoo hashing [],
我不知道 Cuckoo 哈希[]，
but for, to make this multi threaded,
但要使这个变为多线程，
it'd be so much work or just too much work,
它将太多的工作，
to tell two threads,
告诉两个线程，
okay, we're looking this key,
好的，我们在找这个键，
you hash it this way,
你这样哈希它，
I'll hash it this way,
我会这样哈希它，
and then to then synchronize on who produces back result,
然后同步谁产生了结果，
that is just not worth it.
不值得这样做。
Yes.
是的。
So your question is,
所以你的问题是，
do you have to guarantee that the hash function.
你必须保证哈希函数。
Yes.
是的。
So, so do you have to guarantee your hash function can't do that,
所以，你必须保证你的哈希函数不能这样做，
you can't, right,
你不能，
that's, that's why I'm saying you want to choose a hash function that has a low collision rate,
这就是为什么我说你想要选择一个碰撞率低的哈希函数，
so the like, you can't guarantee that won't happen,
你不能保证这不会发生，
but the likelihood that that it will happen is low,
但可以保证它会发生的可能性是低的，
the only thing you can get to is a perfect hash function.
你唯一能得到的就是一个完美的哈希函数。
His question,
他的问题，
does it default to linear probe hashing, what do you mean?
它默认是线性探测哈希吗，你是什么意思？
Oh, if I, if I run out locations for this,
哦，如果我跑出这个位置，
either because all the slots are full
要么是因为所有的 slot 都满了，
or I get a wrap around when I try to do the cuckoo thing,
要么是我试图做 Cuckoo 时绕回，
you double the size of it.
你把它的大小加倍。
Yeah, so his question is,
是的，所以他的问题是，
is there a defined order,
是否有一个定义的顺序，
such that like you can maybe just always check the first hash,
比如你可以总是检查第一个哈希，
like I'm showing two lines coming out of it,
我显示的是两行，
but in, in a assume it's not parallel,
但在假设它，不平行的情况下，
it is executing sequentially,
它是按顺序执行的，
like could I, is there some protocol, say, check this,
比如，有什么协议，检查这个，
and then only fetch the page for the second one,
然后，只获取第二个页面，
if I if I know it's not going to be there,
如果我知道它不会在那里，
I mean, you can do a bunch of everything,
我的意思是，你可以做很多事情，
so you could prefetch the second page, right,
这样你就可以预取第二页，
because the hashing is actually cheap,
因为哈希实际上很便宜。
it's the lookup is expensive, right,
查找是很昂贵的，
so maybe I I could choose one that,
所以也许我我可以选一个，
I have two page IDs I went into look up,
我有两个页面 ID ，我去查了一下，
so if I have a way to go which one actually exists first,
所以，如果我有一个方法，首先检查哪个存在，
maybe go check that one, prefetch the other one,
也许去检查那一下，预取另一个，
again, it depends on the implementation.
同样，这取决于实现。
But, but it depending on what got inserted and how you think, got moving around,
但是，这取决于插入的是什么和你是如何移动的，
like, you know, but the fact that we're coming up with sort of so many.
但事实是我们提出了这么多。
Is there another woman,
有别的女人吗，
is going to bathroom,
是要上厕所吗，
what is he doing?
他在干什么？
Anyway, yeah.
无论什么，是的。
So the fact we coming of different ways to do this,
所以我们有不同的方式来做这件事，
it shows how complicated is where linear probe hashing,
这表明线性探测哈希是多复杂，
you just kind of [] through it, right?
你只是有点[]它。
This question is,
这个问题是，
in a general system, what, what is the default,
在一般系统中，默认的是什么，
I don't know, we can go look up on David's code,
我不知道，我们可以去查一下 David 的代码，
default, it might be three,
默认可能是[三]，
I have no idea, yeah.
我不知道，是的。
All Right.
好的。
I want to get through the chain hashing,
我想讨论一下链式哈希，
because we'll need this for one of the projects.
因为我们的其中一个项目需要这个。
So again, all of these protocols I've showed so far,
所以，到目前为止，我展示的所有这些协议，
these are all static hashing schemes,
都是静态哈希方案，
again, if we run out of space or we loop back around,
如果我们耗尽了空间或循环返回，
then we need to double the size of the hash table and repopulate it,
那么我们需要将哈希表的大小加倍并重新填充它，
and that's expensive.
这是很昂贵的。
So we will now talk about different techniques to incrementally resize the hash table
所以，我们现在将讨论不同的技术来增量地调整哈希表的大小，
without having to rebuild the entire thing.
而不必重建整个哈希表。
So the most common one going to be chain hashing,
最常见的方法是链式哈希，
and again, this is what most people think of when you think about hash tables sometimes
当你想到哈希表时，大多数人都会想到这个，
and then, but we'll look at two more advanced techniques,
然后我们看看两种更高级的技术，
that actually are used in real systems.
在实际系统中所使用的。
So chain hashing, the basic idea is that,
所以链式哈希的基本思想是，
instead of having this giant array of all the slots where we actually insert keys,
不是包含我们插入键的所有 slot 的巨大数组，
array is just going to be pointers to essentially link lists or chains or buckets,
数组将是指向链表或链或桶的指针，
where all the keys that map to that slot in our hash table
在我们的哈希表中映射到该 slot 的所有键
will be found in that in that linked list, right,
都将在那个链表中的 slot 中找到，
if you allocate a hashmap in Java,
如果你在 Java 中分配一个 hashmap ，
this is essentially what you get.
这就是你所得到的。
And so the, the linked list part can essentially grow infinitely,
链表部分基本上可以无限增长，
because again, in the worst case scenario,
因为在最坏的情况下，
all my keys hash to the same slot,
我的所有键都哈希到同一个 slot ，
I'm, I'm just appending to this giant list
我只是添加到这个巨大的列表中，
and I'm, I'm falling down or basically end up with a sequential scan,
我落在，或者最终是以顺序扫描，
but again, ideally if I have a hash function that's good,
但是，理想情况下，如果我有一个好的哈希函数，
I won't, I'll have a good distribution of keys.
我不会，我会有一个很好的键分发。
The way to think about this is,
考虑这一点的方法是，
we're essentially partitioning our giant hash table we have before
我们实际上是在对我们的之前有的巨型哈希表进行分区，
into smaller hash tables themselves, or smaller tables,
分成了更小的哈希表本身，或者更小的表，
we can get unique keys doing the same tricks we did before,
我们可以用我们以前做过的同样的技巧来获得唯一的键，
just keep appending the redundant keys to this giant list,
只要继续把多余的键添加到这个巨大的列表中，
we can still use tombstones,
我们仍然可以使用墓碑，
but oftentimes compaction is just faster in this case.
但在这种情况下，压缩通常会更快。
All right, so now again we have, here we have our bucket pointers
好的，现在我们有了桶指针，
and this is where hash functions are going to hash into,
这就是哈希函数要哈希的地方，
and then these are just be pointers to the different buckets that exist,
然后这些只是指向存在的不同桶的指针，
so if we want to put A in,
所以如果我们想把 A 放进去，
we hash it, mod it by the number of bucket pointers we have
我们哈希它，用我们拥有的桶指针的数量来对它取模，
and then we land in that bucket,
然后我们就落在那个桶里，
we find the first free slot and we just insert it, right.
我们找到第一个空闲的 slot ，然后将其插入。
Same thing, going to put B,
同样的，放入 B ，
B goes to the top here just as before,
B 就像以前一样放在顶部，
and then now, in case C,
现在，对于 C 的情况，
C hashes to the same bucket where A is located,
C 哈希到 A 所在的同一个桶，
we just scan through sequentially
我们只需顺序扫描，
until we find the first free slot.
直到找到第一个空闲 slot 。
Take a call?
接了个电话？
You put D and d goes where where A is,
你放入 D ， D 到了 A 的位置，
it scans through all the slots are empty,
它扫过所有的 slot 都是空的，
you can put something in the page header
你可以在页头中放一些东西，
and say I have no more free slots,
然后说我没有更多的空闲 slot ，
therefore, always expand me, when you get to me, it doesn't matter,
因此，当你到达我时，总是要扩展我，这不重要，
and then basically this page here will then point to another page,
然后，这个页面将指向另一个页面，
where you can find D.
在那里你可以找到 D 。
And then we want to put E
然后我们想把 E 放在后面，
and follow through until we find E here, right.
直到我们在这里找到 E 。
And f can go here.
F 可以放在这里。
So again, the nice thing about this is that,
这样做的好处是，
I can grow the the key list within a bucket
我可以在一个桶中增加键列表，
without affecting other parts of the, of the table,
而不会影响表的其他部分，
but, you can have a sort of like two level, two level hash tables,
但是，你可以有一个两级的哈希表，
where like this is a hash table,
比如这样是一个哈希表，
that takes you into these buckets another hash table,
把你带到另一个哈希表的这些桶中，
but simplicity, we're just showing it as as a linked list like this.
但是为了简单起见，我们只是把它显示为一个链表。
But doing that,
但这样做，
yes, question.
是的，问题。
His question is,
他的问题是，
when you create a new bucket,
当你创建一个新的桶时，
how do you determine the size of it?
如何确定它的大小？
We're not talking about whether,
我们不是在讨论，
for this lecture, we haven't talked about whether something,
在这节课上，我们没有讨论一些东西，
like backed by pages from on disk or in memory,
磁盘上或内存中的页面支持，
but like if it is a,
但如果它是，
assume it's backed by pages that are on disk and on buffer pool,
假设它是由磁盘上的页面和缓冲池支持的，
so if whatever the page size in the database,
无论数据库中的页面大小是多少，
that'll be the page size of a bucket,
都是桶的页面大小，
so in Postgres is 8 kilobytes,
在 Postgres 中是 8 千字节，
MySQL is 16 kilobytes, right.
MySQL 是 16 千字节。
I'm showing within one page two, two keys,
我在一个页面展示了两个键，
because it's powerpoint.
因为它是幻灯片。
So again, if I have a lot of keys, hash in the same location,
再说一次，如果我有很多键，哈希在同一个位置，
this linear scan here can be expensive,
这种线性扫描可能会很昂贵，
so actually a really simple optimization you can do is,
实际上，你可以做一个非常简单的优化是，
in your bucket pointer list,
在你的桶指针列表中，
you also store a Bloom filter,
你还可以存储布隆过滤器，
that just tells you whether a key exists in in my linked list,
这告诉你，在我的链接列表中是否存在一个键，
so if I want to look up now G,
所以，如果我现在想要查找 G ，
I first check the Bloom filter,
我首先检查布隆过滤器，
I ask it whether it exists or not,
我问它是否存在，
if yes, then then I'll keep following the pointer
如果是，那么我将继续沿着指针前进，
and go, then scan along to I find the thing I'm looking for,
然后扫描到我寻找的东西，
if not, if it says no,
如果不是，如果它说不是，
then I don't do that scan,
那我就不做扫描了，
so that avoids that, having to do that extra traversal.
这就避免了不得不进行额外的遍历。
Do everyone know what a Bloom filter is?
大家都知道布隆过滤器是什么吗？
No, okay,
不，好的，
so I asked, Hold up.
所以我就问了，等一下。
Bloom filters are awesome
布隆过滤器很棒，
and be useful for a bunch of things.
对很多东西都很有用。
All right, quickly,
好的，快一点，
a Bloom filter is a probabilistic data structure,
布隆过滤器是一种概率数据结构，
that can tell you that can answer set membership queries,
它可以告诉你，可以回答集合成员身份查询，
so a filter is different than an index,
过滤器不同于索引，
an index tells you,
索引告诉你，
for a given key, where is it,
对于给定的键，它在哪里，
in this record ID, in this page,
在这个记录 ID 中，在这个页面中，
a filter can only say,
过滤器只能说，
does the key exist, yes or no,
键是否存在，是还是不是，
can't tell you where it is,
不能告诉你它在哪里，
it just tells you whether it exists, right,
它只能告诉你它是否存在，
so a, a Bloom filter,
所以布隆过滤器，
the guy was named Bloom, I think from the 70s,
这个人叫布隆，我想是从七十年代开始的，
so the the bloom filterter is a probabilistic data structure,
所以布隆过滤器是一个概率数据结构，
meaning like, it can tell you with with hundred percent percent correctness,
这意味着它可以百分之百正确地告诉你，
that a key does not exist,
一个键不存在，
but if you say, it can tell you that a key does exist
但如果你，它可以告诉你键存在，
and it might actually be wrong
它可能实际上是错误的，
and give you false positives,
并给你假的肯定，
and you can only do two operations on the basic Bloom filter,
你只能在基本的布隆过滤器上做两个操作，
you can do an insert and you can do a lookup,
你可以执行 insert 和 lookup ，
you can't do deletes,
你不能执行 delete ，
we'll see why.
我们会知道为什么。
So it basically just think of like most of all it just a bitmap, right,
所以基本上可以认为它只是一个位图，
and a bit will be set based on the keys that get inserted,
并且将根据插入的键来设置位，
so say I start inserting members of the Wu-Tang Clan,
假设我开始插入 Wu-Tang Clan 的成员，
so I insert RZA
所以我插入 RZA ，
and so I'll have the hash functions,
所以我会有哈希函数，
I'll hash it again,
我将再次对其进行哈希，
same hash implementation, just a different seed,
相同的哈希实现，只是不同的种子，
I get some hash value out
我得到了一些哈希值，
and then I mod it by the number of bits that I have in my my Bloom filter,
然后根据我的布隆滤器中的位数对其进行取模，
and then whatever that number is, I set those bits to 1,
然后不管这个数字是什么，我都会将这些位设置为 1 ，
flip it from 0 to 1,
把它从 0 翻转到 1 ，
I insert GZA,
我插入 GZA ，
same thing, hash it,
同样的东西，对其进行哈希，
mod by the number of bits and set those bits to 1,
对位数取模，并将这些位设置为 1 ，
now if I want to do a lookup on RZA,
现在如果我想查看 RZA ，
same thing, I just do a,
同样的东西，我只是做，
hash the key I'm looking for, mod the number
哈希我要查找的键，对位数取模，
and then I go check to see,
然后我去检查，
whether all the bits, bit locations that I I've hashed to,
是否我哈希的所有位的位置，
if they're set to 1,
它们是否设置为 1 ，
then I know this was set,
那么我知道这是设置，
if it's set to 1,
如果它设置为 1 ，
then I I I think it could exist,
那么我认为它可能存在，
but I could be wrong,
但我可能错了，
because something else might have set those bits, right,
因为可能是其他东西设置了这些位，
so I'll get back TRUE for this,
所以，对于这个，我会得到 TRUE ，
if I do lookup Raekwon, the Chef,
如果我查找 Raekwon, Chef ，
again, when I do a look up,
同样，当我进行查找时，
one of the bits is set to 0,
其中一位被设置为 0 ，
so I know that cannot have been inserted,
所以我知道不可能插入，
because otherwise one of those bits, all those bits would have been set,
因为否则这些位中的一位，所有这些位都会被设置，
so I get FALSE,
所以我得到了 FALSE ，
but I lookup ODB, rest in peace,
但我查找 ODB ，已经去世了，
again, now I can get a false positive,
现在我得到一个假的肯定，
because I never inserted it,
因为我从未插入它，
but his bits were set to 1,
但是他的位被设置为 1 ，
therefore it's TRUE, but it's actually wrong.
因此，这是 TRUE ，但实际上是错的。
So you can put that Bloom filter in front of your bucket chain,
所以你可以把那个布隆过滤器放在你的[桶链]前面，
and that, and it'll be populated with the bits set for the keys that are actually inserted into it,
然后，它将填充为实际插入到其中的键设置的位，
and I can maintain it incrementally,
我可以增量地维护它，
because every time I insert a new key into that bucket list,
因为每次我在桶列表中插入新的键时，
I update my Bloom filter, right.
我都会更新我的布隆过滤器。
There's different variations of Bloom filters,
布隆过滤器有不同的变体，
you can have different levels of them,
你可以有不同级别的它们，
you have decaying ones,
你有衰减的，
the size of the Bloom filters can, can vary them hash functions,
布隆过滤器的大小可以改变它们的哈希函数，
there's a whole bunch of different things,
有一大堆不同的东西，
but like this data structure is super useful,
但像这样的数据结构是非常有用的，
as we use all throughout the system.
我们在整个系统中使用。
Yes. His question is,
是的。他的问题是，
how does the rate false, rate false positive change,
假的肯定率是怎么变化的，
as you [set] the Bloom filter,
当你[设置]布隆过滤器时，
there's some formula that says,
有一些公式说，
like for if you want like a 1% false positive rate,
如果你想要 1% 的假的肯定率，
you need to have a Bloom filter of this size
你需要有一个这种大小的布隆过滤器，
and, and, but this [] hash function.
但这个[]哈希函数。
His question is exponential or linear,
他的问题是指数的还是线性的，
I don't know, I don't remember,
我不知道，我不记得，
but there,
但是这里，
this website here, the Bloom Filter Calculator,
这个网站在这里，布隆过滤器计算器，
you say what false positive rate you want,
你说你想要的假的肯定率，
how many keys you have
你有多少个键，
and it'll tell you the size of the Bloom you want
它就会告诉你想要的布隆过滤器的大小，
and then the number of hash functions.
然后是哈希函数的数量。
Yes.
是的。
The question is, how does Bloom filter deletion,
问题是，布隆过滤器如何删除，
they don't, right,
它们不删除，是的，
there are variations of them with multi levels you can do it,
它们有多层次的变体，
for basic one, they don't.
对于基本的那个，它们不删除。
And Bloom filter are super useful,
布隆过滤器非常有用，
we'll use throughout the system in a bunch of ways,
我们会在整个系统中以多种方式使用它，
we, we'll use it for hash Joins.
我们用它来做哈希 Join 。
Because again, it's a lot cheaper to go look up,
因为，这是一个便宜得多的查找，
to see is it in my Bloom filter,
查看它是否在我的布隆过滤器中，
than go actually follow a page and look on disk
比实际上跟踪一个页面，并在磁盘上查看，
and see whether something exists or not.
看看东西是否存在。
So a more sophisticated scheme is called extendible hashing,
一个更复杂的方案被称为可扩展哈希，
and this is going to be like chain hashing,
这就像链式哈希一样，
but, we're gonna allow the, the,
但是，我们将允许，
we're gonna be able to split the buckets
我们将能够拆分桶，
to avoid these infinitely long bucket lists
以避免这些无限长的桶列表，
and we're going to split it in such a way,
我们将以这样一种方式拆分它，
that we only, we only need to do it incrementally in a small part of the hash table
我们只需要在哈希表的一小部分中递增，
rather than having to re-rehash everything.
而不必重新哈希所有内容。
And the key idea of this is going to work is that,
这个方法的关键思想是，
we're going to expand the number of bits we have to look at,
我们要扩展我们必须查看的位数，
when we do lookups in our in our bucket list or bucket hash table
当我们在桶列表或桶哈希表中查找时，
to go find the, the bucket chain that we're looking for,
以找到我们要查找的桶链，
and we can vary this per, sort of per value, per key type,
我们可以对每个键类型改变它，
not key type, we can vary this based on what bucket list we're looking at,
不是键类型，我们可以根据我们看到的桶列表来改变这个，
so it may be the case that,
所以情况可能是这样的，
two different locations, multiple locations in our in our bucket array will point to the same bucket list,
两个不同的位置，在我们的桶数组中的多个位置，将指向同一个桶列表，
but then that can expand and break up
但是它可以扩展和分解，
as we need it as we go along.
随着我们的需要。
So I I didn't actually think,
所以我并不认为，
this is, this is a bit complicated
这有点复杂，
and I didn't think any system actually uses it,
我不认为任何系统真正使用它，
but it turns out GDBM, which is the GNU database manager,
但事实是 GDBM ，也就是 GNU 数据库管理器，
think of like you know a key value store,
可以认为是一个键值存储，
that like sort of like RocksDB or SQLite,
比如 RocksDB 或 SQLite ，
you can run this and embedded in your system,
你可以运行这个程序，并嵌入到你的系统中，
that database tie you on like extendible hash tables
这个数据库将你连接到可扩展哈希表上，
and then AsteriskDB is a, is a big data project at a UC Irvine
然后 AsteriskDB 是 UC Irvine 的一个大数据项目，
and they have and they're using extendible hashing in their implementation, right.
他们在他们的实现中使用了可扩展哈希。
So let's see how this works.
让我们看看这是如何工作的。
All right, so the first thing we're going to have is that,
好的，我们首先要做的是，
we have our slot array
我们有 slot 数组，
and it's going to point to our bucket list,
它将指向我们的 bucket 列表，
and then we're going to have this global identifier,
然后我们将有一个全局标识符，
that tells us how many bits we need to look at for our hash values
它告诉我们需要查找多少位来查找哈希值，
to determine how we do our lookups in our bucket array,
以确定如何在桶数组中进行查找，
and then for sort of bookkeeping reasons,
然后出于[记账]的原因，
every bucket list as well will also have what our local bit bit size is,
每个桶列表中也将包含我们的本地位大小，
number bits they need to look at.
它们需要查看的位数。
So you can see in the case here,
所以你可以在这里看到，
these first two slots here,
这里的前两个 slot ，
they're both going to be pointing to the same bucket list,
它们都指向相同的桶列表，
whereas these two ones at the bottom,
而底部的这两个，
they're going to be pointing to different locations,
它们指向不同的位置，
and this is because the,
这是因为，
we need to look at,
我们需要查看，
globally, we're going to look at two bits,
全局上，我们将查看两个位，
but for the, the first two entries,
但对于前两个条目，
when the when the bit is 0,
当位为 0 时，
they're going to reuse the same, the same bucket list,
它们将重复使用相同的桶列表，
identified by the the local identifier up here.
由本地标识符来标识。
So let's say now I want to do a look up on on this key here,
现在假设我们想要查看这个键，
I hash it,
我哈希它，
and then look at the top two bits,
然后我查看最上面的两位，
because that's what set my my global identifier, global counter,
因为它设置了我的全局标识符，全局计数器，
and then I hash to this location,
然后我哈希到这个位置，
I just follow the pointer
我只需跟随指针，
and I land in that bucket
然后落在那个桶里，
and I can just do the linear search
我就可以进行线性搜索，
to find the thing I'm looking for.
找到我正在寻找的东西。
Say now I want to put B,
假设现在我想放入 B ，
B, again, globally, I know I need to look at the top two bits,
B ，再次在全局上，我需要看看上面的两个部分，
I do a look up at my, my [], my bucket, my bucket list,
我查找我的桶列表，
based on those two bits,
基于这两个位，
then I land into this location here,
然后我落在这里这个地方，
I go ahead and insert it.
我继续并插入它。
But now I want to put C in,
但现在我想放入 C ，
and if I look at the last two bits,
如果我看最后两个位，
it lands in the same location when I inserted B,
它落在我插入 B 时的相同位置，
but now this bucket is full,
但现在这个桶是满的，
I can't put any more entries in,
我不能再放入更多的条目，
so I need to expand the number of bits I'm looking at
所以我需要扩展我正在查看的位数，
to now expand the number of options that I have,
以扩展我拥有的选项数，
so I'm going to increment the global counter to from 2 to 3,
所以我要将全局计数器从 2 增加到 3 ，
I'm going to double the size of the number of pointers I have in my bucket array,
我将把桶数组中的指针数增加一倍，
but then create the new entry,
然后创建新的条目，
but then the when the bit is set to 0,
但是当位设置为 0 时，
they're all still going to point to the first bucket here,
它们仍然指向这里的第一个桶，
because I haven't that one yet,
因为我还没有那个桶，
so I I need to look at one bit for that,
所以我需要为它寻找一个位，
for the next, when the bits are 111,
对于下一个，当位是 111 时，
that points to this other bucket down here
它指向下面的另一个桶，
and the same thing for these other ones, right.
其他的也是一样的。
So now when I want to do a lookup to put C in,
所以现在，当我想要进行查找放入 C 时，
I need to look at three bits,
我需要查看三个位，
I followed that pointer here,
我顺着那个指针，
that then takes me to this bucket location.
走到了这个桶的位置。
So going back here,
所以回到这里，
when I did my split,
当我进行拆分时，
I had to resize,
我必须调整大小，
these guys just slid down
这些家伙滑下去，
and I only had to insert one new bucket,
我只需要插入一个新的桶，
but I took what was here,
但我获取这里的东西，
because this one was full
因为这个是满的，
and I just split that one
我只是把那个f拆分，
and created the new bucket for it,
然后为它创建了一个新的桶，
I didn't have to touch the one at the bottom
我不需要访问底部的那个，
and didn't have to touch the one at the top,
也不需要访问顶部的那个，
I do have to double the size of this,
我确实要把这个的大小翻倍，
but that,
但那是，
you have to take a latch on it when you do it,
当你这样做的时候，你必须锁住它，
because you have to make a copy and resize it,
因为你必须复制并调整它的大小，
but it's not It's not that big of a deal,
这没什么大不了的，
you can do that pretty quickly.
你可以很快做到这个。
Any questions about this?
对于这个，有什么问题吗？
Is this good?
这个好吗？
So, resizing this slot array is relatively cheap,
所以，调整这种 slot 数组的大小相对便宜，
it's clever, it's a good idea,
这很聪明，这是个好主意，
it's a clever idea,
这是一个聪明的主意，
whether or not it's good or not,
不管它是好是坏，
it, engineering wise,
它，从工程角度来说，
it's a bit tricky to keep track of all the metadata,
跟踪所有元数据的位置有点棘手，
where like you know what, what bits I need to be looking at as a hash into it,
我需要看什么位，作为对它的哈希，
but it's basically just chain hashing,
但这基本上只是链式哈希，
so all the benefits I get from chain hashing are applicable here,
所以，我从链式哈希中获得的所有好处都适用于这里，
I have an extra mechanism now to split things up,
我现在有一个额外的机制来拆分东西，
so I don't have this infinitely growing, you know, linked list,
这样我就不会有无限增长的链表，
so it's just a way to handle incremental resizing
所以，这只是一种处理增量调整大小的方法，
in a way you couldn't do in regular chain hashing.
以一种普通链式哈希中做不到的方法。
Yes.
是的。
I think.
我认为。
Yeah, again, linear probing is probably the easiest thing to do
是的，线性探测可能是最容易做的事情，
and lock the whole table and double the size of it,
锁定整个表并使其大小翻倍，
sometimes it's good enough.
有时候已经足够好了。
All right, so the last one is linear hashing,
好的，最后一种是线性哈希，
and this is actually what Postgres does,
这实际上就是 Postgres 所做的，
something very close to this.
非常接近这个的东西。
And the reason why Postgres,
为什么 Postgres （这么做）的原因，
well, there another about Berkeley DB that also does this,
好的，另一个 Bekeley DB 也做了这个，
the the company that built Berkeley DB was a company called Sleepycat Software,
创建 Berkeley DB 的公司是一家名为 Sleepycat Software 的公司，
so the people that built WiredTiger,
所以，创建 WiredTiger 的人，
they, they, they, they originally started Sleepycat, that got sold to Oracle,
他们最初创建了 Sleepycat ，后来卖给了 Oracle ，
so Oracle own Berkeley DB
所以 Oracle 拥有 Berkeley DB ，
and then they went out and started the new company
然后他们走出去，开始了新的公司，
instead of calling a Sleepycat called a WiredTiger,
不是叫 Sleepycat ，而是叫 WiredTiger ，
like a like you know, tiger on [] or whatever,
就像[]的老虎，
it was trying to be the opposite,
它试图相反，
but, but the the woman that wrote the linear hashing implementation in Postgres in the early 90s,
但是，但是在 90 年代早期为 Postgres 编写线性哈希实现的女人，
was the founder of Berkeley DB,
是 Berkeley DB 的创始人，
so she wrote it for Postgres
所以她为 Postgres 写了它，
and then wrote it for Berkeley DB,
然后为 Berkeley DB 写了它，
all right, and she was one of Stonebraker [] students, at Berkeley.
她是 Stonebraker 在 Berkeley 的一名学生。
So the way, linear hashing can be more complicated than extendible hashing, potentially,
所以，线性哈希可能比可扩展哈希更复杂，
but, the basic idea is that,
但是，基本的想法是，
we're going to keep track of the next, next bucket list we want to split,
我们要跟踪下一个我们要拆分的桶列表，
and that when any time there's an overflow in our, in our bucket list chain
并且当任何时候在我们的桶列表链有溢出时，
and anywhere in our hash table,
在我们的哈希表中的任何地方，
whatever we're pointing at with our split pointer,
无论我们拆分指针指向什么，
that's the one we're going to split.
那就是我们要拆分的。
And the idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
again, we want to do this incrementally
我们想增量地做这件事，
and not have to lock the whole table while we resize,
而不是在调整大小时锁定整个表，
so we can make small changes as we go along.
这样我们就可以在进行时做一些小的修改。
And the idea here is,
这里的想法是，
again, you're amortizing the cost of resizing,
你摊销了调整大小的成本，
so like, it's sort of shared across multiple workers,
就像它是在多个 worker 之间分摊的，
so there's only one worker who's the unlucky one that shows up,
所以只有一个不幸的 worker 出现，
tries to insert something,
试图插入一些东西，
and then, you know, they draw the short straw
然后，它们抽到了短签，
and they're responsible for resizing the whole thing,
它们要对调整整个大小的事情负责，
you do it incrementally as you go along,
你在进行的过程中逐步地做，
and that sort of smooths out performance.
这样会使性能变得平滑。
So again, the idea here is that,
所以，这里的想法是，
we're going to, we're gonna, we're gonna be able to split a,
我们会拆分，
split whatever the next one we need is split,
拆分下一个我们需要拆分的，
which may not be the one that overflowed,
这可能不是溢出的，
it should be whatever the next one is in, in our incremental order,
它应该是按照我们的递增顺序的下一个，
and then we'll have maintain multiple hash functions,
然后我们需要维护多个哈希函数，
that that are gonna help us determine,
这些函数将帮助我们确定，
which location within our bucket list we should be looking at.
在我们的桶列表中，我们应该关注哪个位置。
Let me share the diagram and this makes more sense.
让我来分享这张图表，让这更有意义。
So again, just look before,
所以，在我们开始之前先看看，
we have, we have our bucket list here,
我们这里有我们的桶列表，
and that's going to map to bucket chains,
它将映射到桶链，
and then we're going have a split pointer,
然后我们会有一个拆分指针，
that's going to say,
它会说，
here's the next thing we want to split anytime,
这是我们想要随时拆分的下一个东西，
anything overflows in our hash, hash table,
我们的哈希表中的会溢出的任何东西，
and then we have, at the very beginning,
然后，在最开始，我们有，
we assume we have one hash function,
我们假设我们有一个哈希函数，
that's just the key, the key mod by n, for simplicity reasons,
只有键对 n 取模，为了简单起见，
but again, assuming it's taking any arbitrary string or any arbitrary byte sequence
但再次假设它接受任意字符串或任意字节序列，
and spitting out integer.
并产生整数。
So say I want to, I want to get 6,
假设我想要获取 6 ，
I do my lookup and at 2
我在 2 做我的查找，
and I follow along and I find the key I'm looking for,
我跟随着，找到了我查找的键，
that looks just like before, nothing special,
看起来和以前一样，没有什么特别的，
but now I want to put 17
但现在我想放 17 ，
and it should go into this bucket here,
它应该放到这个桶里，
but that thing is full,
但那个东西已经满了，
so we're just going to do an overflow,
所以我们只是要做一个溢出，
just like chain hashing to extend it with another, another bucket
就像链哈希一样，用另一个桶来扩展它，
and insert it into the, insert it into that new page,
并将它插入到新页面中，
but now, because we overflowed,
但是现在，因为我们已经溢出了，
we need to split whatever the split pointer I was pointing at,
我们都需要拆分，无论拆分指针指向哪里，
so in this case here,
所以在本例中，
it's pointing to bucket 0, bucket list 0,
它指向桶列表 0 ，
even though that didn't overflow,
即使它没有溢出，
so what we need to do now is
所以我们现在需要做的是，
look at all the entries inside this bucket list,
查看这个桶列表中的所有条目，
and we're going to rehash them based on the 2n,
然后我们将基于 2n 对它们进行重新哈希，
because we're going to incrementally grow the size of the bucket list by one each time,
因为我们每次都会递增一个桶列表的大小，
so we had four entries,
所以我们有四个条目，
now, after we got to split, now we'll have five,
现在，在我们拆分之后，我们将有五个，
so we go through and this points there,
所以我们遍历，这个指向那里，
for every single key,
对于每个单独的键，
we're going to rehash it,
我们将重新哈希它，
based on, on, instead of mod n, but mod two n,
基于，不是对 n ，而是对 2n 取模，
so 8 mod 8 is 0,
所以 8 对 8 取模是 0 ，
so that stays where it was,
所以它停留在它的地方，
20 mod 8 is now 4,
20 对 8 取模现在是 4 ，
so that's going to get moved down to this new page down here, right,
所以它将被移到下面这一页，
and then now the split pointer just moves down by one,
然后现在拆分指针向下移动一位，
and we continue doing whatever,
我们将继续执行，
you know, continue operating on the hash table, right.
在哈希表上继续执行操作。
so now I do get 20,
所以现在执行获取 20 ，
I first, when I first hash it, I would get 0,
当我第一次哈希它的时候，我会得到 0 ，
but then I know that, that location in my, my bucket list here
但我知道那个位置在我的桶列表这里，
is above where the split pointer is pointing at,
在拆分指针指向的上方，
so I know I've already splitted everything up above it,
我知道我已经把上面的所有东西都拆分了，
so after I mod by 4,
所以在我对 4 取模之后，
I got a mod by 8 now,
现在我对 8 取模，
to figure out where it really is,
以确定它的实际位置，
and then that's how I can find it down here at the bottom.
然后就是我如何在底部找到它的方法。
Say I want to get 9,
假设我想获取 9 ，
in this case here,
在这种情况下，
it's pointing to exactly where the bucket the split pointer is pointing at,
它指向拆分指针所指向的桶的位置，
so I know I haven't split it yet,
所以我还没有拆分它，
so I can just only hash it once
所以我只对它进行一次哈希，
and I scan along the link list
然后沿着链表扫描，
until I find the thing I'm looking for.
直到找到我要找的东西。
And at some point, the split pointer will get to the bottom,
在某一时刻，拆分指针将到达底部，
and I'll have, I'll have 8 slots
我将有八个 slot ，
and I just loop back around and start all over again.
我只是循环回来，从头开始。
So this seems kind of counterintuitive that,
所以这看起来有点违反直觉，
like I'm not splitting the thing that overflowed,
好像我没有拆分溢出的东西，
I'm splitting to whatever the split pointer points at,
我拆分到拆分指针所指向的位置，
but the idea is again that,
但我们的想法是，
if you say this location 1,
如果你说这个位置 1 ，
this thing is super hot
这个东西非常热，
and I keep overflowing, overflowing,
我不停地溢出，溢出，
I'm eventually going to split it, right,
我最终会拆分它，
so eventually, everything gets split out and resize correctly.
最终，所有东西都会被拆分并正确地调整大小。
Yes.
是的。
So the question is when,
所以问题是，
when would it actually wrap around, because [] 1,
什么时候它会绕回，因为[]1 ，
so you would get to the pointer like,
你就会到达指针，
so it'd be 5, 6, 7,
所以它是 5 6 7 ，
and then you'll be 7,
然后你就是 7 ，
and then you have to you loop back around to 0,
然后你必须循环回到 0 ，
because you know that,
因为你知道，
from when it's here,
从它在这里的时候，
when it's only from 0 to 3,
当它只从 0 到 3 的时候，
yeah, once you get past 7,
是的，一旦过了 7 ，
you know where you starting point,
你就知道你的起点了，
that's two n from where you started at,
从你开始的地方算起是 2n ，
so then you loop back around.
然后你又循环回来。
You add a new page,
你添加了一个新的页面，
but like, I know that I should wrap around,
但我知道我应该绕过去，
when I get, when I go to 8, at position 8,
当我到达 8 时，在位置 8 ，
because when I started I had 4,
因为我开始的时候，有 4 ，
so 2 times 4 is 8,
所以 2 乘以 4 等于 8 ，
so when I get past 8, I loop back around,
所以当我超过 8 的时候，我循环回来，
then you do that until you get 16
然后你一直这样做，直到你得到 16 ，
and loop back around.
然后循环回来。
Good idea or bad idea?
好主意还是坏主意？
It's clever, right,
这很聪明，对吧，
again, it's, it's a nice technique to do, do this incrementally,
再说一次，这是一个很好的技巧，增量地做这件事，
but again, there's a lot more bookkeeping, a lot more machinery,
但是，有更多的[簿记]，更多的机器，
in order to actually implement those.
为了真正实现这些。
Yes.
是的。
And this question is,
这个问题是，
if you only do when you do look up,
如果你只做查找，
you only had hash it most twice,
你最多只做两次哈希，
in this scenario, yes.
在这个场景中，是的。
Like if, like, if this thing is massive,
如果这个东西很大，
I could have like,
我可以说，
yeah, so actually what happens is,
是的，所以实际上发生的事情是，
once I get to say I got to 8 and I wrap back around,
一旦我说，到达 8 ，我绕回，
I can drop the first hash function,
我可以去掉第一个哈希函数，
yeah, so in this case,
是的，那么在这种情况下，
are you going to hash most two.
你最多会哈希两次。
Yes.
是的。
His question is,
他的问题是，
and here I'm trying to mod by 8,
现在我试着对 8 取模，
but what if I get 7 and I don't have it,
但如果我获取 7 ，但我没有呢，
but again, you, you wouldn't be able to get 7,
但是，你得不到 7 ，
because, you'd be below the split pointer
因为，你会在拆分指针之下，
and you'd only hash by 4, not 8, right,
你只会以 4 哈希，而不是 8 ，
so, so this demarcation line says,
所以，这条分界线是说，
I've split everything above and nothing below,
我把所有东西都拆分到上面，下面什么也没有，
avoids that problem,
避免这个问题，
that you don't land here
你不会落在这里，
and you really like, you don't,
你不会，
you don't hash first and land here,
你不会先哈希，然后落在这里，
but if you hash by 2n,
但如果你对 2n 哈希，
you land something here, you haven't split yet,
你落在这里，你还没有拆分，
the split pointer waterline avoids that problem.
拆分指针水位线避免了这个问题。
All right, so,
好的，所以，
splitting buckets based on the split pointer,
拆分桶基于拆分指针，
eventually gets you all overflow buckets,
最终会导致所有桶溢出，
again, said this, when you reach the bottom,
再次，当你到达底部时，
you just drop the first hash function and loop back around,
你只需丢弃第一个哈希函数，然后循环返回，
the, in this technique,
在这个技巧上，
also allows you to do, contraction or coalescing as well,
也能让你做到缩写或合并，
because you could identify that a bucket list is empty,
因为你可以确定桶列表是空的，
and you could do the reverse,
而你可以做相反的事情，
you could, could could throw it away,
你可以把它扔掉，
consolidate the the one bucket empty,
把空的那个桶[巩固]起来，
so like you could just throw it away
比如你可以扔掉它，
and you move the split pointer back up,
然后把拆分指针向上移动，
and at last, you actually shrink the size of the hash table, right.
最后，你实际上缩小了哈希表的大小。
So going back here,
所以回到这里，
say I delete 20,
假设我删除 20 ，
I mod it by 4,
我把它对 4 取模，
but then I realize that's below the split pointer
但我意识到它在拆分指针的下方，
and I got to get down to the bottom here
我必须深入到底部，
and I go ahead and delete it,
然后继续删除它，
but now this page is empty,
但现在这一页是空的，
so if I wanted to,
所以如果我想，
I could just move the pointer back up
我可以把指针移回去，
and then drop that last entry
然后删除最后一个条目，
and drop the last hash table, right.
删除最后一个哈希表。
And obviously you need to be clever
显然你需要聪明点，
and make sure that like I don't oscillate,
确保我不会振荡，
like insert 20, delete 20, insert 20,
比如，插入 20 ，删除 20 ，插入 20 ，
I keep splitting it and coalescing,
我不断地拆分和合并，
that would be bad.
那就糟了。
But you could contract the data structure based on this, right.
但你可以在这个基础上压缩数据结构。
You don't want to insert 21, then overflow
你不想插入 21 ，然后溢出，
and split all over again.
再一次拆分。
I don't think Postgres supports shrinking the size of the hash table,
我不认为 Postgres 支持缩小哈希表的大小，
as far as I know,
据我所知，
without rebuilding the whole thing.
没有重建整个东西。
All right, so hash tables, again, super useful,
好的，哈希表非常有用，
most systems are going to just implement the linear probe hashing,
大多数系统只实现了线性探测哈希，
but again you can still specialize it
但是，你仍然可以专门化它，
based on the data type and other aspects
根据数据类型以及其他方面，
of how it's going to be used,
关于它如何使用，
and ClickHouse is probably the best example of this,
ClickHouse 可能是这方面最好的例子，
for a lot of the commercial systems,
对于很多商业系统来说，
it's very hard to know what hash table they're actually using,
很难知道他们实际上使用什么哈希表，
unless there's a paper talking about it
除非有一篇论文讨论它，
or we know people that work there that can tell us,
或者我们知道在那里工作的人可以告诉我们，
you know, this is not something you as,
这不是一些事情，
you know someone using SQL, an application developer,
使用 SQL 的人，应用程序开发人员，
you should know or care,
你应该知道或关心的事情，
but it's nice to know what sometimes how these [assessments] are implemented.
但有时知道这些[评估]是如何实现的是很好的。
Nice thing about hash functions again, it'll be fast,
哈希函数的好处是，它会很快，
they'll support O(1) lookup in the best case scenario,
在最好的情况下，它们将支持 O(1) 查找，
but again, we need to be able to make sure that we can,
但同样，我们需要能够确保我们可以，
you know, we, we may need to grow efficiently,
我们可能需要有效地增长，
if we estimate the size incorrectly,
如果我们错误地估计大小，
and we'll see how we do those estimations later on.
我们稍后将看到我们如何做这些估计。
So some systems will give you hash table when you call create index,
所以有些系统会在你调用创建索引的时候给你哈希表，
Postgres will let you do this,
Postgres 会让你做这个，
Postgres be called create index,
Postgres 调用创建索引，
you can say using hash
你可以说使用哈希，
and you'll get a hash table,
你会得到一个哈希表，
You'll get their their linear hash table implemention, right,
你会得到他们的线性哈希表实现，
but this is not the default,
但这并不是默认的，
for, for almost all systems,
对于几乎所有的系统，
when you call create index,
当你调用创建索引时，
is there know why?
有没有人知道为什么？
No range cans, yes,
没有范围[可以]，是的，
the only thing you can do with the hash table is the quality lookups
你唯一使用哈希表能做的就是[质量]查找，
and you need to have the entire key, right,
你需要有整个键，
if my key is on column A and column B,
如果我的键在 A 列和 B 列，
I can do composite keys,
我可以做组合键，
if I don't have A, I don't have B,
如果我没有 A ，我没有 B ，
I can't do a lookup.
我就不能查找了。
In a B+ tree,
在 B+ 树中，
which we'll discuss next class,
我们将在下一节课中讨论，
you can do these prefix lookups
你可以做这些前缀查找，
and it is the best data structure of all time, for databases,
这是有史以来用于数据库最好的数据结构，
Tries are actually pretty good too,
Trie 实际上也很好，
but you can put Tries of B+ trees,
但你可以把 Trie 放入 B+ 树中，
the default choice those systems are going be a B+ tree,
这些系统的默认选择是 B+ 树，
and that's what we'll discuss next week,
这就是我们下周要讨论的问题，
but again, we'll assume it's single threaded, on Monday
但是，在星期一我们将假设它是单线程的，
and then on Wednesday, we'll see how to make it multi threaded.
在星期三，我们将了解如何使其成为多线程的。
All right, hit it.
好的，开始吧。